{
  "Kreuzwoerter": [
    {
      "Frage": "Frage",
      "Antwort": "DING, FALL, BITTE, SACHE, SUJET, LOSUNG, AFFAERE, EROTEMA, PROBLEM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Aal",
      "Antwort": "EEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "aasen",
      "Antwort": "AESEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ABS",
      "Antwort": "ANTIBLOCKIERSYSTEM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ABC",
      "Antwort": "ALPHABET"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Abt",
      "Antwort": "ABATE, BADIA, BANDE, COUPE, GILDE, HARST, ARTIKEL, BEREICH, EINHEIT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Abgabe",
      "Antwort": "GELD, PASS, TAXE, ZOLL, ABSATZ, AKZISE, OBOLUS, STEUER, TRIBUT, ABSPIEL, ABZUEGE, BEITRAG, VERKAUF"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Abteilung",
      "Antwort": "BANDE, HERDE, MENGE, RAYON, RIEGE, ROTTE, ARTIKEL, BEREICH, GATTUNG, KOLONNE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Abschnitt",
      "Antwort": "ENDEN, FOLGE, KOPIE, PUNKT, STUCK, SZENE, ARTIKEL, HAELFTE, PASSAGE, SEKTION"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Abkürzung",
      "Antwort": "ABK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Abnormität",
      "Antwort": "ANOMALIE, ABWEICHUNG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Abmontieren",
      "Antwort": "ABBAUEN, ABMACHEN, ENTFERNEN, DEMONTIEREN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "abkauen",
      "Antwort": "ABESSEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ach",
      "Antwort": "WIRKLICH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Acht",
      "Antwort": "BANN, VERFEMUNG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Acker",
      "Antwort": "ERDE, FELD, FLUR, HUBE, LAND"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Achse",
      "Antwort": "BUND, LIGA, UNION, WELLE, SPINDEL, ZENTRUM, DREHPUNKT, MITTELPUNKT, STAATENBUND"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ackern",
      "Antwort": "RIGOLEN, ROEDELN, PFLUEGEN, SCHUFTEN, UMGRABEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Achten",
      "Antwort": "EHREN, HOREN, ANERKENNEN, BOYKOTTIEREN, RESPEKTIEREN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Achtel",
      "Antwort": "BRUCHTEIL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Adler",
      "Antwort": "AAR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Adventüre",
      "Antwort": "ABENTEUER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Adressant",
      "Antwort": "ABSENDER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Adieu",
      "Antwort": "ADE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "adelig",
      "Antwort": "NOBEL, FEUDAL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Adressiermaschine",
      "Antwort": "ADREMA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Adsorptionsmittel",
      "Antwort": "ADSORBENS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Adlerstein",
      "Antwort": "ADANA, AETIT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Adjutant",
      "Antwort": "HELFER, GEHILFE, ASSISTENT, HILFSKRAFT, STELLVERTRETER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "adelige Dame",
      "Antwort": "EDELFRAU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Addition",
      "Antwort": "SUMMIERUNG, VERMEHRUNG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "addieren",
      "Antwort": "AUFRECHNEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Aera",
      "Antwort": "EPOCHE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Aea",
      "Antwort": "SONNENLAND"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Aerophobie",
      "Antwort": "FLUGANGST"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Affe",
      "Antwort": "LAR, SAI, LORI, MAKI, SAKI, VARI, INDRI, KATTA, LEMUR, MAGOT, MAKAK, POTTO, BABUIN, BONOBO, PAVIAN, PRIMAT, RAUSCH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Affäre",
      "Antwort": "ABFOLGE, LIAISON, SKANDAL, VORFALL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Afrikanerin",
      "Antwort": "GABUNERIN, UGANDERIN, LIBERIANERIN, NIGERIANERIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Affirmation",
      "Antwort": "BEJAHUNG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "afganische Währung",
      "Antwort": "AFN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Jahrbuch",
      "Antwort": "ALMANACH, KALENDER, TAGEBUCH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Afrika, Fluss",
      "Antwort": "DJA, NIL, OMO, KAFUE, KASAI, KASEI, KOMOE, KONGO, NIGER, ARUWIMI, BANDAMA, DSCHUBA, SAMBESI, KOMADUKU, OKAWANKO, SCHELIFF"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Afrikaner",
      "Antwort": "HAMITE, LIBYER, MALIER, SOMALI, TOGOER, GAMBIER, GHANAER, GHANESE, SAMBIER, AEGYPTER, ALGERIER, FARBIGER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "afrikanischer Berg",
      "Antwort": "ADWA, AGOU, ALID, BATU, DEGA, ETJO, KIBO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "afrikanischer Staat, Land",
      "Antwort": "BARKA, BENIN, FAYUM, AMHARA, ANGOLA, GAMBIA, SAMBIA, TSCHAD, BAGIRMI, BEHERAH, LESOTHO, LIBERIA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "afrikanischer Seifenbaum",
      "Antwort": "AKI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "afrikanischer Priester",
      "Antwort": "ALFAKI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "afrikanischer Stamm",
      "Antwort": "AFIFI, BAELE, BANTU, BAULE, FANTI, MASAI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "afrikanischer Vogel",
      "Antwort": "BANDFINK, GOLDWEBER, KONGOPFAU, GRAUPAPAGEI, MADENHACKER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "afrikanische Hauptstadt",
      "Antwort": "ABUJA, ACCRA, AKKRA, DAKAR, KAIRO, RABAT, BAMAKO, HARARE, LUANDA, MALABO, MASERU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zahl",
      "Antwort": "ACHT, EINE, EINS, IHRE, RATE, SANK, ZEHN, ALLER, ALTER, LCHER, LIEGE, LIEGT, REIHE, BETRAG, DIESER, GROSSE, JUNGER, WURZEL, EINHEIT, HUNDERT, SIEBZIG, ZAEHLER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Agon",
      "Antwort": "WETTKAMPF"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Agni",
      "Antwort": "FEUERGOTT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Agil",
      "Antwort": "REGE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Agens",
      "Antwort": "KRAFT, MITTEL, HEILMITTEL, MOTIVATION, TRIEBKRAFT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Agio",
      "Antwort": "AUFGELD"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Agavengewächs",
      "Antwort": "AGAVE, HOSTA, YUCCA, DRACAENA, TUBEROSE, BOGENHANF, GRASLILIE, JOSUABAUM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Agavenbranntwein",
      "Antwort": "MESCAL, MESKAL, MEZCAL, PULQUE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "fortwährend",
      "Antwort": "IMMERSO, IMMERZU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Nachbarschaft",
      "Antwort": "NAEHE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Verhältniswort",
      "Antwort": "ANS, AUF, AUS, BAR, BEI, GEN, INS, MIT, VON, VOR, AUFS, BEIM, DANK, FERN, FUER, LANG, SAMT, DURCH, FUERS, GEGEN, KRAFT, LINKS, MEIST"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Ruf Renommee",
      "Antwort": "ANSEHEN, LEUMUND"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stadt an der Ems NRW",
      "Antwort": "LOEHNE, RHEINE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Germane",
      "Antwort": "AMBRONE, BATAVAR, CHAUKEN, HERULER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Farbton",
      "Antwort": "AZUR, BLAU, BLEU, FALB, GRAU, KIWI, PINK, CHAMOIS, COULEUR, KORALLE, ORPHEUS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Staat der USA",
      "Antwort": "IDAHO, MAINE, TEXAS, ALASKA, CANSAS, HAWAII, KANSAS, NEVADA, ALABAMA, ARIZONA, GEORGIA, MONTANA, LOUISIANA, NEUMEXIKO, NEWMEXICO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kupfer Zink Legierung",
      "Antwort": "TOMBAK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Abkürzung für ehrenhalber",
      "Antwort": "EH, HC"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Vorderasiat",
      "Antwort": "KURDE, KYRER, PARSE, SAUDI, SYRER, ARABER, IRAKER, IRANER, LIBYER, TUERKE, AFGHANE, ISRAELI, JEMENIT, KATARER, AEGYPTER, GEORGIER, TURKMENE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Unabhängigkeit",
      "Antwort": "AUTARKIE, FREIHEIT, FREIRAUM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Antillenbewohner",
      "Antwort": "KUBANER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Täuschung, Straftat",
      "Antwort": "BETRUG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "afrikanischer Staat",
      "Antwort": "BENIN, GABUN, GHANA, KENIA, KENJA, ZAIRE, BISSAU, CISKEI, DAHOME, LIBYEN, SAMBIA, BURUNDI, DAHOMEY, ERITREA, KAMERUN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "baumlose Graslandschaft",
      "Antwort": "STEPPE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "übermenschliches Wesen",
      "Antwort": "GOTT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Regierungsform",
      "Antwort": "REGIME, SYSTEM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "kurze, witzige Geschichte",
      "Antwort": "ANEKDOTE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wagenbespannung",
      "Antwort": "PLANE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Herrschertitel",
      "Antwort": "DESPOT, HERZOG, KOENIG, KONUNG, SULTAN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Geliebte",
      "Antwort": "BUHLE, DONJA, HOLDE, KALLE, LIEBE, PUPPE, BEKANNTE, DULCINEA, LIEBCHEN, KONKUBINE, MAETRESSE, MAITRESSE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Geschäftszimmer",
      "Antwort": "BUERO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fluss zur Donau",
      "Antwort": "AIST, DRAU, EGAU, ISAR, NAAB, SHIT, SKIT, ABENS, CERNA, EIPEL, GUENZ, LEIBI, REGEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Beingelenk",
      "Antwort": "KNIE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stufengestell",
      "Antwort": "ETAGERE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Festungswerk",
      "Antwort": "BURG, FORT, VAUX, BASTEI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "tschechischer Komponist",
      "Antwort": "BURIAN, CIKKER, KASLIK, KLUSAK, VACKAR, JANACEK, KALABIS, MARTINU, STAMITZ"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wegbiegung",
      "Antwort": "KEHRE, KURVE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Sinnbild der Würde und Macht",
      "Antwort": "KRONE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "hochsteigen, klimmen",
      "Antwort": "KLETTERN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Feingebäck",
      "Antwort": "KEKSE, TARTE, TORTE, KRAPFEN, MAKRONE, PRALINE, WAFFELN, HEFEZOPF, NUSSECKE, SCHNECKE, HEIDESAND, OBSTTORTE, TORTELETT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zeitungsabonnent",
      "Antwort": "LESER, BEZIEHER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Meinungsforscher",
      "Antwort": "DEMOSKOP"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Englisches Seebad und Hafen",
      "Antwort": "DOVER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Teil Innerasiens",
      "Antwort": "ALTAI, NEPAL, PAMIR, TIBET"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Ausweis",
      "Antwort": "PASS, PAPIER, PAPIERE, KENNKARTE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "altrömische Kalendertage",
      "Antwort": "IDEN, IDUS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Sittenlehre",
      "Antwort": "ETHIK, MORAL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gesichtsfärbung",
      "Antwort": "ROETE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Verwaltungsbehörde eines Landes",
      "Antwort": "MINISTERIUM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "einerlei, gleichartig",
      "Antwort": "DITO, EGAL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stadt in Nebraska",
      "Antwort": "ADAMS, AGNEW, ALDEN, ALLEN, CRETE, OMAHA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zuspruch, Aufmunterung",
      "Antwort": "TROST"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fluss durch Berlin",
      "Antwort": "DAHME, HAVEL, PANKE, SPREE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "nagender Kummer",
      "Antwort": "GRAM, HARM, PEIN, QUAL, ZRAM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ebenfalls",
      "Antwort": "AUCH, DITO, ITEM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Straßenbelag",
      "Antwort": "ASPHALT, BITUMEN, MAKADAM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stadt in Mähren",
      "Antwort": "IGLAN, IGLAU, ZNAIM, BRUENN, OSTRAU, PRERAU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "zu hoch angesetzt",
      "Antwort": "UEBERHOEHT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zierlatte",
      "Antwort": "LEISTE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Spiel, Wettkampfklasse",
      "Antwort": "LIGA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "kleinkörniges Getreide",
      "Antwort": "HIRSE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zauberwurzel",
      "Antwort": "ALRAUN, ALRAUNE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Teil des Mittelmeeres",
      "Antwort": "ADRIA, SYRTE, AEGAEIS, RIVIERA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fluss durch München",
      "Antwort": "ISAR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gartenzierpflanze",
      "Antwort": "DALIEN, GERMER, RESEDE, TULPEN, ZINNIE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Grundform des Jazz",
      "Antwort": "BLUES, SWING"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "europäischer Strom",
      "Antwort": "AGRI, BEGA, GERS, ISAR, LECH, LOIR, NEWA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Nutzen, Gewinn",
      "Antwort": "ERTRAG, PROFIT, VORTEIL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gebetsschlusswort",
      "Antwort": "AMEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Italienische Stadt",
      "Antwort": "BOZEN, DELIA, EDOLO, FONDI, GRADO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Leiterin eines Nonnenklosters",
      "Antwort": "OBERIN, AEBTISSIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Autosignalgerät",
      "Antwort": "HORN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Oper von Verdi",
      "Antwort": "ATTILA, IRSINI, KORSAR, OBERTO, OPERTO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schlechtwetterzone",
      "Antwort": "TIEF"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "fertig gekocht",
      "Antwort": "GAR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "griechische Göttin",
      "Antwort": "ATE, BIA, DEO, EOS, INO, KER, LNO, NYX, ASIA, AURA, LUNA, MUSA, OSSA, RHEA, STYX"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "schweizer Kupferstecher",
      "Antwort": "AMSLER, CASPAR, MECHEL, MERIAN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Paladin Karls des Großen",
      "Antwort": "ALFONS, GAREIN, OLIVER, REIMES, TURPIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Propagandist",
      "Antwort": "WERBER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ohne Inhalt",
      "Antwort": "HOHL, INAN, LEER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stadt an der Ruhr NRW",
      "Antwort": "ARNSBERG, MESCHEDE, MUELHEIM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "sich irgendwo aufhalten",
      "Antwort": "WEILEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Würde, Ansehen",
      "Antwort": "EHRE, RUHM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Singstimme",
      "Antwort": "ALT, BASS, SOPRAN, STIMME, BARITON"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Klavierteil",
      "Antwort": "PEDAL, SAITE, TASTE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Trödler, Müßiggänger",
      "Antwort": "BUMMLER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Lebensbund",
      "Antwort": "EHE, EHEN, EHESTAND, MISCHEHE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "tröpfeln, rieseln",
      "Antwort": "REGNEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wintersportler",
      "Antwort": "AAS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "eine der Musen",
      "Antwort": "CLIO, KLIO, AOEDE, AOIDE, ARCHE, ASOPO, ERATO, NEILO, ETANEA, HYPATE, MELETE, THALIA, URANIA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fluss im Sauerland",
      "Antwort": "ENNEPE, FRETTE, HOENNE, HUNDEM, MOEHNE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "selten, knapp",
      "Antwort": "RAR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "belgischer Kurort",
      "Antwort": "AVE, SPA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "griechisch: Luft",
      "Antwort": "AER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Satz beim Tennis",
      "Antwort": "SET"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "früherer äthiopischer Titel",
      "Antwort": "RAS, NEGUS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Ruf, Renommee",
      "Antwort": "ANSEHEN, LEUMUND"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Ringelwurm",
      "Antwort": "EGEL, PIER, TIER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "französische Herrscheranrede",
      "Antwort": "SARE, SIRE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Ausruf der Verwunderung",
      "Antwort": "ACH, HUI, OCH, OHO, OJE, NANU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "langweilig, schal",
      "Antwort": "FADE, OEDE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Nische in einer Gaststätte",
      "Antwort": "SEPAREE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "bunte Unterhaltungsdarbietung",
      "Antwort": "SHOW"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "organische Verbindung, Essigäther",
      "Antwort": "ESTER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "poetisch: Kopf",
      "Antwort": "HAUPT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "stetig, ununterbrochen",
      "Antwort": "IMMER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Blasinstrument",
      "Antwort": "DUDA, HORN, LAPA, OBOE, SAXO, TIBA, ZINK, BUSINE, CARNYX, CORNET, FAGOTT, POMMER, MATALAN, RACKETT, RANKETT, SALPINX"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Jurist",
      "Antwort": "NOTAR, ANWALT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "englischer Artikel",
      "Antwort": "THE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ungesetzlich",
      "Antwort": "ILIEGAL, ILLEGAL, ILLOYAL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Brennstoff",
      "Antwort": "HOLZ, KIEN, KOKS, PECH, TORF, BENZIN, BIOGAS, ERDGAS, ERDOEL, ERDOIL, NATURGAS, STADTGAS, GRUDEKOKS, MAISSTROH, PROPANGAS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zeichen für Radium",
      "Antwort": "RA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "persönliches Fürwort",
      "Antwort": "DIR, ICH, IHM, IHN, IHR, MIR, SIE, UNS, WEM, WIR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Spion, Spitzel",
      "Antwort": "AGENT, VMANN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Orchesterleiter",
      "Antwort": "LAST, DIRIGENT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "niederländische Stadt",
      "Antwort": "AMELO, ASSEE, ASSEN, EELDE, LISSE, MARUM, BOXTEL, ERMELO, HUIZEN, MUIDEN, RHENEN, ALKMAAR, ARNHEIM, DENHAAG, EERBEEK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Pastete aus Fleisch oder Obst",
      "Antwort": "PIE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Teil des Flugplatzes",
      "Antwort": "ROLLBAHN, ROLLFELD"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "spanischer Artikel",
      "Antwort": "EL, EN, ET, IL, LA, LO, LAS, LOS, UNA, UNE, UNO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zahlwort",
      "Antwort": "ACHT, DREI, EINS, NEUN, NULL, VIER, ZEHN, ACHTE, FUENF, SECHS, ACHTZEHN, DREISSIG, NEUNZEHN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zeichen für Eisen",
      "Antwort": "FE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "englisch: Mädchen",
      "Antwort": "CHIT, GIRL, LASS, MAID"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "männliches Pferd",
      "Antwort": "HENGST"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "langes Bootsruder",
      "Antwort": "SKULL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Neuordnung",
      "Antwort": "REFORM, WANDEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Lichtbild",
      "Antwort": "DIA, FOTO, PHOTO, AUFNAHME, FARBFOTO, PASSFOTO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wohnraum eines Schiffes",
      "Antwort": "KABINE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Jordanische Hauptstadt",
      "Antwort": "AMMAN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "chemisches Element",
      "Antwort": "BLEI, GOLD, NEON, SINK, THOR, URAN, ZINK, ARGON, ARSEN, AURUM, AZOTE, CHLOR, RADON, BARIUM, BISMUT, OSMIUM, THORON, WISMUT, BOHRIUM, KRYPTON, LITHIUM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Insel vor der Südküste Chinas",
      "Antwort": "HAINAN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "elektrisches Stromstärkemaß",
      "Antwort": "AMPERE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "lateinisch: im Jahre",
      "Antwort": "ANNO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "kostspielige Lebensführung",
      "Antwort": "LUXUS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zündschnur",
      "Antwort": "LUNTE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Abendgesellschaft",
      "Antwort": "CERCLE, SOIREE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Himmelsrichtung",
      "Antwort": "OST, NORD, SUED, WEST, OSTEN, NORDEN, SUEDEN, WESTEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "männliches Borstentier",
      "Antwort": "EBER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zuverlässigkeit",
      "Antwort": "TREUE, VERLASS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "somit, mithin",
      "Antwort": "ALSO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Mischling",
      "Antwort": "BASTARD, CASTIZE, HYBRIDE, KASTIZE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Thema, Gegenstand einer Dichtung",
      "Antwort": "SUJET"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "geringes Ausmaß",
      "Antwort": "KLEIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gemüts, Gefühlslage",
      "Antwort": "STIMMUNG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wirkung, Erfolg",
      "Antwort": "EFFEKT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Farb, Arzneigrundstoff",
      "Antwort": "ANILIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "kleines, einfaches Lokal",
      "Antwort": "BUDIKE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "bebend (Musik)",
      "Antwort": "VIBRATO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "altgermanisches Schriftzeichen",
      "Antwort": "RUNE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Geliebter der Hero",
      "Antwort": "LEANDER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "weibliches Bühnenfach",
      "Antwort": "ALTE, HEXE, BOESE, NAIVE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "furchtsam, besorgt",
      "Antwort": "BANG, BANGE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Dummkopf",
      "Antwort": "DALK, DEPP, GANS, GECK, JECK, KALB, ROSS, DODEL, HEINI, HIRNI, IDIOT, NULPE, TROPF, HAMMEL, KAFFER, KRETIN, LACKEL, NARREN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Abfall, Kehricht",
      "Antwort": "DRECK, MUELL, STAUB, UNRAT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "sprechen, sich äußern",
      "Antwort": "REDEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "wechselseitig",
      "Antwort": "AUPAIR, MUTUAL, MUTUEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Indiens",
      "Antwort": "DEHLI, DELHI, NEUDEHLI, NEUDELHI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Reichsritter und Humanist",
      "Antwort": "HUTTEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "oberdeutsch: Lawine",
      "Antwort": "LAUE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Flachland",
      "Antwort": "EBENE, SENKE, TAFEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Einfassung",
      "Antwort": "RAHMEN, VOLANT, ZARGEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fischfanggerät",
      "Antwort": "ANGEL, BUNGE, ELGER, HAKEN, HAMEN, REUSE, BUGNETZ, HARPUNE, KESCHER, ZUGNETZ, EISANGEL, KAESCHER, LEGANGEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "wirklich",
      "Antwort": "ABER, ECHT, GANZ, REAL, REIN, WAHR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Arztbesuch",
      "Antwort": "VISITE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Auszeichnung, Gewinn",
      "Antwort": "EHRENPREIS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Musikstück",
      "Antwort": "FUGE, LIED, OPUS, TANZ, TRIO, WERK, ADAGIO, CHORAL, FUGATO, HYMNUS, TEDEUM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Insektenlarve",
      "Antwort": "MADE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Theaterplatz",
      "Antwort": "LOGE, RANG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "deutscher Chemiker",
      "Antwort": "AUER, BABO, BERL, HEIN, HOCK, MUNK, RUER, ABEGG, BOSCH, BUNTE, LUNGE, STORR, THILO, DIEHLS, HEEREN, MIETHE, NERNST"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hundeschar",
      "Antwort": "MEUTE, RUDEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Lufttrübung",
      "Antwort": "DAMPF, DUNST, NEBEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "zu etwas taugen, passen",
      "Antwort": "EIGNEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stadt und Fluss in Böhmen",
      "Antwort": "EGER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "sich täuschen",
      "Antwort": "IRREN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Inhaltslosigkeit",
      "Antwort": "LEERE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kreuzesinschrift",
      "Antwort": "INRI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Klosterneuling",
      "Antwort": "NOVICE, NOVIZE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "kleiner Junge (Kosewort)",
      "Antwort": "BUBE, BUBI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schlaginstrument, Gong",
      "Antwort": "TAMTAM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kinderpflegerin",
      "Antwort": "BONNE, NURSE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "britischer Sagenkönig",
      "Antwort": "LEAR, ARTUS, MINOS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "französischer Schriftsteller",
      "Antwort": "ADAM, AJAR, ALYN, ANET, ARON, BLAU, HUGO, STIL, BAYLE, BILLY, BOUGY"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "französischer Autor",
      "Antwort": "BLOY, FLEG, INOR, IZZO, MERY, URFE, WERN, CABUS, COMTE, FAGUS, JOUVE, LISLE, LOUYS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Baumbestand an Flüssen",
      "Antwort": "AUWALD"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "schmale Stelle",
      "Antwort": "ENGE, ENGPASS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "altrömisches Gewand",
      "Antwort": "TOGA, ENTARI, TUNICA, TUNIKA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Ratsherr",
      "Antwort": "SENATOR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Raubkatze",
      "Antwort": "FOSSA, IRBIS, KUDER, LOEWE, MANUL, ZIBET, GEPARD, JAGUAR, KUGUAR, PANTER, SERVAL, LEOPARD, PANTHER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "griechische Göttin der Zwietracht",
      "Antwort": "ERIS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "einfarbig",
      "Antwort": "UNI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Lärm, Krach",
      "Antwort": "RADAU, RUMOR, TRARA, GEPOLTER, GERATTER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Landenge von Malakka",
      "Antwort": "KRA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "feurig, temperamentvoll",
      "Antwort": "RASSIG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kanton der Schweiz",
      "Antwort": "WAADT, LUZERN, SCHWYZ, TICINO, VALAIS, WALLIS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Edelgas",
      "Antwort": "NEON, ARGON, BUTAN, NITON, RADON, XENON"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Laufvogel",
      "Antwort": "EMU, MOA, KASUAR, TRAPPE, STRAUSS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kältemittel",
      "Antwort": "FREON"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "jetzt",
      "Antwort": "NUN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zeitgeschmack",
      "Antwort": "LOOK, MODE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "auf der anderen Seite",
      "Antwort": "DRUEBEN, VISAVIS, HINUEBER, JENSEITS, UMSEITIG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "US-Raumfahrtbehörde",
      "Antwort": "NASA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Glücksgöttin",
      "Antwort": "TYCHE, FORTUNA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "banktechnischer Begriff",
      "Antwort": "DISKONT, INKASSO, KONKURS, SOLVENZ"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "scheitern",
      "Antwort": "PLATZEN, ERLIEGEN, STOLPERN, VERSAGEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "finnischer Läufer",
      "Antwort": "NURMI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wasserstelle für Tiere",
      "Antwort": "TRAENKE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "handeln",
      "Antwort": "AGIEREN, ANGEHEN, MANAGEN, MARKTEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Richterspruch",
      "Antwort": "URTEIL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "jeder ohne Ausnahme",
      "Antwort": "ALLE, ALLESAMT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "landwirtschaftliches Gerät",
      "Antwort": "EGGE, KAMA, GABEL, HACKE, HARKE, PFLUG, SCHAR, SENSE, HECKSLER, HEUFORKE, HEUGABEL, MELKEIMER, MELKSTAND, SCHREDDER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "alkoholisches Getränk",
      "Antwort": "ARAK, ASTI, BIER, GOSE, GROG, JOPE, KOEM, BRANDY"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Molkerei",
      "Antwort": "MEIEREI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "waagerechte Stange am Mast",
      "Antwort": "RAH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "lichtes Rosa",
      "Antwort": "PINK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "schlechte Gewohnheit",
      "Antwort": "UNSITTE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gebirge zwischen Europa und Asien",
      "Antwort": "URAL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "englische Prinzessin",
      "Antwort": "ANNE, KATE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Äußerung",
      "Antwort": "AUSSAGE, EINWURF, HINWEIS, VERBALE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Sinnesorgan",
      "Antwort": "OHR, AUGE, HAUT, NASE, NERV"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Sportgerät",
      "Antwort": "BALKEN, BARREN, HAMMER, HANTEL, SAEBEL, BAENDER, BILLARD, BUECHSE, MINIBOB"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Begriff der Popmusik",
      "Antwort": "BEAT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Teil von Vietnam",
      "Antwort": "ANNAM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gedenkfeier",
      "Antwort": "EHRENTAG, GEDENKEN, MEMORIAL, JAHRESTAG, JUBILAEUM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Ei der Laus",
      "Antwort": "NISSE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "leichter Schuh mit Riemen",
      "Antwort": "SANDALE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wertpapier",
      "Antwort": "AKTIE, BRIEF, SHARE, TALON, VALOR, BLUECHIP, EFFEKTEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Göttin des Herdfeuers",
      "Antwort": "VESTA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Autobahngaststätte",
      "Antwort": "GASTHOF, RASTHOF, RASTHAUS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fleisch in einer Gallertmasse",
      "Antwort": "SUELZE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fleischspeise",
      "Antwort": "BEIRIED, BULETTE, HASCHEE, KASSLER, BOULETTE, KASSELER, KOTELETT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fluss, Bach",
      "Antwort": "ACHE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "bayrischer Wintersportort",
      "Antwort": "INZELL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "hessische Stadt an der Fulda",
      "Antwort": "BEBRA, FULDA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Herr, Herrscher",
      "Antwort": "GEBIETER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Raubtier",
      "Antwort": "BAER, HUND, LYNX, MINK, NERZ, PUMA, RATZ, FOSSA, FUCHS, KUDER, KUGAR, MELON, MUNGO, BAERIN, KOJOTE, OZELOT, PARDEL, PARDER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Begleitmannschaft",
      "Antwort": "ESKORTE, GEFOLGE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Musikinstrument des Clown",
      "Antwort": "KONZERTINA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wehgeschrei",
      "Antwort": "KLAGE, ZETER, GEZETER, LAMENTO, ZETEREI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "in einem Krankenhaus tätiger Arzt",
      "Antwort": "KLINIKER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Werk von Homer",
      "Antwort": "ILIAS, ILIADE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wendepunkt",
      "Antwort": "EPOCHE, GIPFEL, KRISIS, MARKSTEIN, PERIPETIE, TIEFPUNKT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schuldsumme, Pflichtgebot",
      "Antwort": "SOLL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "vertraut",
      "Antwort": "INNIG, INTIM, TRAUT, BEKANNT, DISKRET, GEWOHNT, VOLUBEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ungefähr, annähernd-",
      "Antwort": "ETWA, FAST, RUND, CIRCA, ZIRKA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ohne Milde, hart",
      "Antwort": "STRENG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "kleines Lasttier",
      "Antwort": "ESEL, MULI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "zu sprießen beginnen",
      "Antwort": "KEIMEN, GRUENEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "französische Stadt an der Loire",
      "Antwort": "BLOIS, TOURS, ANGERS, BRIARE, NAHLES, NANTES, SAUMUR, AMBOISE, ORLEANS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "fest zusammenbinden",
      "Antwort": "ZURREN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Abkürzung für Landgericht",
      "Antwort": "LG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kooperation",
      "Antwort": "ALLIANZ, LIAISON, VERBUND"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "anbaufähig",
      "Antwort": "URBAR, URBAU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "französisch: danke",
      "Antwort": "MERCI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Tochter des Ödipus",
      "Antwort": "ISMENE, ANTIGONE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Geschäft, Werk",
      "Antwort": "BETRIEB"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Urschrift",
      "Antwort": "ORIGINAL, URFASSUNG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Menschenraub",
      "Antwort": "PIRATERIE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Mittagsruhe",
      "Antwort": "SIESTA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Berührungslinie",
      "Antwort": "TANGENTE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Spaßmacher",
      "Antwort": "KASPAR, KASPER, SCHALK, SCHELM, BAJAZZO, BOUFFON, HOFNARR, KASPERL, HARLEKIN, HASELANT, WITZBOLD"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ungarische Steppe",
      "Antwort": "PUSSTA, PUSZTA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zunge am Schuh",
      "Antwort": "LASCHE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Milchkäse",
      "Antwort": "QUARK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fahrwasserkundiger",
      "Antwort": "LOTSE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Geometrische Figur",
      "Antwort": "KEGEL, KREIS, KUBUS, KUGEL, RAUTE, STERN, ELFECK, PRISMA, QUADER, TRAPEZ, ACHTECK, ANKREIS, INKREIS, PARABEL, FUENFECK, HYPERBEL, PYRAMIDE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "essbare Pflanzen",
      "Antwort": "AMARANT, GEMUESE, GIERSCH, RUCCOLA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Signalfarbe",
      "Antwort": "ROT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Luftwedel",
      "Antwort": "FAECHER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "amerikanische Viehfarm",
      "Antwort": "RANCH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "begeisterter Anhänger",
      "Antwort": "FAN, FANS, BEWUNDERER, ENTHUSIAST, SCHWAERMER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "türkische Stadt",
      "Antwort": "EMET, ENOS, INES, INEZ, KARS, ORDU, USAK, AFYON, BAFRA, BELEK, BIGHA, BURSA, SINOP, AMASYA, ARTVIN, BAFIRA, KANGAL, MANISA, BERGAMA, ERZURUM, ISPARTE, MALATYA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "eine Ware bestellen",
      "Antwort": "ORDERN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "deutscher Autor",
      "Antwort": "CUBE, ENDE, EYTH, HABE, HEYM, MANN, MUTH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Lastschiff",
      "Antwort": "FRACHTER, LEICHTER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "griechische Göttin der Morgenröte",
      "Antwort": "EOS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stoß mit dem Fuß",
      "Antwort": "TRITT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Begriff beim Kartenspiel",
      "Antwort": "ATOUT, GRAND, GRUEN, POINT, STICH, TALON, FEHLFARBE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Handwerkervereinigung",
      "Antwort": "GILDE, ZUNFT, INNUNG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fischatmungsorgan",
      "Antwort": "KIEME"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "dem Adel angehörend",
      "Antwort": "ADLIG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kraftstoff auffüllen",
      "Antwort": "TANKEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "anfänglich",
      "Antwort": "ERST"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Abkürzung für United Nations",
      "Antwort": "UN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "schmal, begrenzt",
      "Antwort": "ENG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Unempfänglich, gefeit",
      "Antwort": "IMMUN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "zirpendes Insekt",
      "Antwort": "GRILLE, ZIKADE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "erforderlich",
      "Antwort": "NOETIG, BINDEND, GEBOTEN, OBLIGAT, WICHTIG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schmuckstein",
      "Antwort": "JUWEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Rockmusikstil",
      "Antwort": "PUNK, FUSION, GRUNGE, FOLKROCK, SOFTROCK, SOULROCK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "dreist, vorlaut",
      "Antwort": "KESS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fluss zur Rhone",
      "Antwort": "BERRE, CANEA, DROME, ISERE, MORGE, SAONE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stadt und See in Pennsylvania",
      "Antwort": "ERIE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fanatiker",
      "Antwort": "EIFERER, KAMPFER, RASSIST, ZELOTEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "leicht regnen",
      "Antwort": "NIESELN, SPRUEHEN, TROEPFELN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schneehütte",
      "Antwort": "IGLU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ausreichend",
      "Antwort": "GENUG, KNAPP, ESGEHT, ANNEHMBAR, GENUEGEND, GEZIEMEND"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Bindewort",
      "Antwort": "ALS, BIS, EHE, MIT, NUN, NUR, UND, WIE, ABER, ALSO, AUCH, DANN, DOCH, ERGO, ODER, ANDEM, BEVOR, DAHER, INDEM, SOWIE, WOHER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Essen, Gericht",
      "Antwort": "MAHL, IMBISS, SPEISE, VESPER, SCHMAUS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Holzgewächs",
      "Antwort": "ARBE, ARVE, BAUM, EIBE, ERLE, ESPE, HURA, AHORN, BUCHE, BUCHS, ELLER, ESCHE, WEIDE, EIBISCH, LORBEER, SCHLEHE, STRAUCH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schienenweg",
      "Antwort": "TRASSE, STRECKE, TRASSEE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fehllos",
      "Antwort": "NIETE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Adliger",
      "Antwort": "BARON, EDLER, EDELMANN, ARISTOKRAT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Ernährung, Verpflegung",
      "Antwort": "KOST"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Heer, Heeresdienst (umgangssprachlich)",
      "Antwort": "KOMMISS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "griechischer Buchstabe",
      "Antwort": "MY"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Senke im Gelände",
      "Antwort": "TAL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Unterarmknochen",
      "Antwort": "ELLE, ULNA, HUMERUS, SPEICHE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "trainieren",
      "Antwort": "UEBEN, BERATEN, COACHEN, DRILLEN, TRIMMEN, ARBEITEN, BETREUEN, EINUEBEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Bruder Jakobs",
      "Antwort": "ESAU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Vornehmtuer",
      "Antwort": "KLIO, SNOB"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "symbolisches Schmuckstück",
      "Antwort": "EHERING, TRAURING"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "anhänglich",
      "Antwort": "BRAV, TREU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Grund, Ursache",
      "Antwort": "ANLASS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kriechtier",
      "Antwort": "KOBRA, LURCH, MAMBA, OTTER, SKINK, WARAN, GAVIAL, KAIMAN, LEGUAN, NATTER, REPTIL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "auslöschen, ausmerzen",
      "Antwort": "TILGEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Denksportaufgabe",
      "Antwort": "LOGICAL, RAETSEL, QUIZFRAGE, RAETSELEI, RATESPIEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Barrenquerstange",
      "Antwort": "HOLM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Sand, Schneeanhäufung",
      "Antwort": "WALL, WEHE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "bayrische Benediktinerabtei",
      "Antwort": "ETTAL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Ausspannung von Arbeitskräften",
      "Antwort": "ABWERBUNG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Chef, Vorgesetzter (umgangssprachlich)",
      "Antwort": "BOSS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zustand der Lufthülle",
      "Antwort": "WETTER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "nordische Münze",
      "Antwort": "OERE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "englisch: Schritt",
      "Antwort": "PACE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gefängnis",
      "Antwort": "BAU, KISTE, KNAST, ARREST, BUNKER, KARZER, KASTEN, KERKER, KITTCHEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zupfinstrument",
      "Antwort": "DOMRA, GUSLI, KOBZA, LEIER, TRANH, TUBUS, CISTER, CUATRO, KINNER, KINNOR, ZITHER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Bescheinigung eines Arztes",
      "Antwort": "ATTEST"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hühnerprodukt",
      "Antwort": "EI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ostslawisches Volk",
      "Antwort": "RUSSEN, RUSSINEN, UKRAINER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Presskohle",
      "Antwort": "BRIKETT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wochenende (englisch)",
      "Antwort": "WEEKEND"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "fahl, bleich",
      "Antwort": "BLASS, ASCHGRAU, BLUTLEER, GLANZLOS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Getreideart",
      "Antwort": "DARA, DARI, KORN, MAIS, RAPS, REIS, TEFF, DURRA, EMMER, FENCH, FESEN, HAFER, HIRSE, DINKEL, DURRHA, GERSTE, ROGGEN, SORGHO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wüste in Innerasien",
      "Antwort": "GOBI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ohne Zuversicht",
      "Antwort": "MUTLOS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fechthieb",
      "Antwort": "FILO, PLIE, PRIM, SIXT, TERZ, FINTE, LINIE, OKTAV, PRIEM, QUART, STICH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Vorliebe, Schwäche",
      "Antwort": "FAIBLE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "wärmeloser Zustand",
      "Antwort": "KAELTE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Eintreffen, Ankommen",
      "Antwort": "ANKUNFT, ANLANGEN, ANREISEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "politischer Zusammenschluss",
      "Antwort": "FUSION, PARTEI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zitterpappel",
      "Antwort": "ASPE, ESPE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Monatsletzter",
      "Antwort": "ULTIMO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Märchenwesen",
      "Antwort": "FEE, NIX, OLE, PER, ELFE, FEEN, HEXE, MAHR, MOHR, NIXE, OGER, DRUDE, ELFEN, ENGEL, FATME, PRINZ, TROLL, DAEMON, GRETEL, OBERON"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "selbstloser Mensch",
      "Antwort": "ALTRUIST, IDEALIST"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Flüssigkeit zu sich nehmen",
      "Antwort": "TRINKEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "niedersächsische Stadt an der Elbe",
      "Antwort": "STADE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "singen oder pfeifen",
      "Antwort": "TRILLERN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "englisches Handelsgewicht",
      "Antwort": "DRAM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schifffahrtskunde",
      "Antwort": "NAUTIK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Bartschergerät",
      "Antwort": "RASIERER, RASIERAPPARAT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "holländische Stadt",
      "Antwort": "EDE, EDI, ELM, EPE, AKKRUM, BEMMEL, BERGEN, ERMELO, GELEEN, ALKMAAR, DRONTEN, EERBEEK, HAARLEM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "eine der Musen",
      "Antwort": "CLIO, KLIO, AOEDE, AOIDE, ARCHE, ASOPO, ERATO, NEILO, ETANEA, HYPATE, MELETE, THALIA, URANIA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Heerwesen",
      "Antwort": "MILITAER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "deutsche Nordseeinsel",
      "Antwort": "AMRUM, DUENE, FANOE, HABEL, HOOGE, OLAND"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Holzflößung",
      "Antwort": "TRIFT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Pferd",
      "Antwort": "ROSS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "besonders extrem",
      "Antwort": "KRASS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stoß (besonders beim Fußball)",
      "Antwort": "REMPLER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Dach, Kellerfenster",
      "Antwort": "LUKE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "marokkanische Hafenstadt",
      "Antwort": "SAFI, SALE, AGADIR, TANGER, TETUAN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "langes Kleid",
      "Antwort": "MAXI, SARI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "heftiger Unwille",
      "Antwort": "WUT, ZORN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hafen in Aserbeidschan",
      "Antwort": "BAKU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "dunkelbraune Farbe",
      "Antwort": "UMBER, UMBRA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ein Raum im Haus",
      "Antwort": "KUECHE, ESSKUECHE, ESSZIMMER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gleichförmigkeit",
      "Antwort": "EBENMASS, EINERLEI, EINKLANG, LANGWEILE, MONOTONIE, SYMMETRIE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zirkusschauplatz",
      "Antwort": "ARENA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Behälter, Hülle",
      "Antwort": "ETUI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "früherer Name Thailands",
      "Antwort": "SIAM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zögling",
      "Antwort": "ELEVE, ALUMNE, ELEVIN, KADETT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Handelsplatz",
      "Antwort": "BASAR, BAZAR, DEPOT, HAFEN, LAGER, MARKT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Biene",
      "Antwort": "IMME"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wagenschuppen",
      "Antwort": "GARAGE, REMISE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ungezogenes Mädchen",
      "Antwort": "DIRNE, FRATZ, GOERE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Vorsilbe: zwischen",
      "Antwort": "INTER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Begrenzungslinie",
      "Antwort": "GRENZE, KONTUR, UMFANG, UMRISS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "aufgedruckter Betrag (Aktie)",
      "Antwort": "NENNWERT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "österreichischer Lyriker",
      "Antwort": "ADLER, BUSTA, DEMUS, JANDL, RILKE, TRAKL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hab, Raffsucht",
      "Antwort": "GIER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Tierpflege",
      "Antwort": "HEGE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kautabak",
      "Antwort": "BETEL, PRIEM, TWIST"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Länder Vorderasiens",
      "Antwort": "NAHOST"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fluss zur Elbe",
      "Antwort": "AIPA, AUPA, EGER, EHLE, IHLE, OHRA, SUDE, ADLER, ALAND, BIELA, BILLE, JAHNA, STOER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ukrainischer Schwarzmeerhafen",
      "Antwort": "ODESSA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schönwetterzone",
      "Antwort": "HOCH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Lanzenreiter",
      "Antwort": "ULAN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Äußerung zurücknehmen",
      "Antwort": "WIDERRUFEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Heilkundiger",
      "Antwort": "NATURARZT, NEUROLOGE, OHRENARZT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Metallbolzen",
      "Antwort": "NIET"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "biblischer Stammvater",
      "Antwort": "ADAM, ENAK, ESAU, HARN, LEVI, NOAH, SETH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Teil des Essservices",
      "Antwort": "TELLER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hunnenkönig Attila",
      "Antwort": "ETZEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gleitbahn, Förderanlage",
      "Antwort": "RUTSCHE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kosakenpeitsche",
      "Antwort": "NAGAIKA, NAGAJKA, NAJAJKA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Geliebte des Zeus",
      "Antwort": "AGAE, ARGE, HERA, HORA, MAIA, MAJA, RHEA, ALBUM, ARGOS, DANAE, METIS, RAMIE, SALAT, AEGINA, AIGINA, PYTHON, THALIA, THEMIS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "deutlich",
      "Antwort": "DERB, KLAR, SEHR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Urwaldpflanze",
      "Antwort": "AGAVE, CANNA, KAKAO, LIANE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Bodenfläche, Gelände",
      "Antwort": "AREAL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Tierkreiszeichen",
      "Antwort": "FISCH, KREBS, LOEWE, STIER, VIRGO, WAAGE, FISCHE, WIDDER, JUNGFRAU, SCHUETZE, SKORPION, STEINBOCK, ZWILLINGE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zirkusmanege",
      "Antwort": "ARENA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "englische Dynastie",
      "Antwort": "TUDOR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fahrzeug",
      "Antwort": "BARKE, BREAK, JOLLE, MOBIL, MOPED, BALLON, BRUMMI, CHAISE, MOKICK, SCHIFF"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Nachkommenschaft aus Eiern",
      "Antwort": "BRUT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ukrainische Halbinsel",
      "Antwort": "KRIM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Rundholz, Segelstange",
      "Antwort": "SPIERE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Besucher",
      "Antwort": "GAST"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Opernsologesang",
      "Antwort": "ARIE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Südslawe",
      "Antwort": "RAIZE, SERBE, GORANE, KROATE, POMAKE, RAITZE, SEWERE, BULGARE, KROATEN, SEVERER, SEWERER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Bewohner des Deutschen Reiches",
      "Antwort": "PREUSSE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Enterich",
      "Antwort": "ERPEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Sinnbild, Kennzeichen",
      "Antwort": "EMBLEM, ENBLEM, SYMBOL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Delphinart",
      "Antwort": "INIA, GRINDWAL, TUEMMLER, WEISSWAL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gewässerrand",
      "Antwort": "DAMM, FELS, MOLE, PIER, UFER, WEHR, GESTADE, OSTUFER, SEEUFER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "englische Königin",
      "Antwort": "MARY, MARIA, QUEEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Segelbaum",
      "Antwort": "MAST"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Tapferkeit",
      "Antwort": "MUT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Anmut, Liebreiz",
      "Antwort": "APPEAL, CHARME, GRAZIE, ZAUBER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stein mit eingeschnittenem Bild",
      "Antwort": "GEMME"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gefühlslage",
      "Antwort": "EMOTION, GEFUEHL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "getrocknete Weinbeere",
      "Antwort": "ROSINE, KORINTHE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Saiteninstrument",
      "Antwort": "CELLO, DOMRA, PIANO, POCHE, VIOLA, VIOWA, BANDOLA, BANDURA, CEMBALO, KLAMPFE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Telefonat",
      "Antwort": "ANRUF"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Langspieß",
      "Antwort": "PIKE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Haustiere",
      "Antwort": "EBER, ENTE, ESEL, HUND, VIEH, BULLE, GEISS, HASEN, HENNE, HUNDE, PUTER, GANTER, RINDER, TAUBER, WIDDER, ZICKEL, KANINCHEN, KARNICKEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "wolliges Gewebe",
      "Antwort": "FLAUS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Puste",
      "Antwort": "ATEM, LUFT, HAUCH, ATMUNG, ATEMLUFT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Singvogel",
      "Antwort": "AMMER, IORAS, LORAS, LORIS, MEISE, MOHOS, AMMERN, AMSELN, GIMPEL, STELZE, AMARANT, ASTRILD, PELTOPS, ROTFINK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Lohn in Naturalien",
      "Antwort": "DEPUTAT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gerte, Stöckchen",
      "Antwort": "RUTE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Eislaufdisziplin",
      "Antwort": "EISTANZ"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Maultier",
      "Antwort": "ESEL, MULI, MULUS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wassersportart",
      "Antwort": "ANGELN, JETSKI, KURORT, RUDERN, SEGELN, PADDELN, RAFTING, SURFING, TAUCHEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Feldertrag",
      "Antwort": "ERNTE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Verwandter",
      "Antwort": "AGNAT, EIDAM, ENKEL, GATTE, NEFFE, OHEIM, KUSINE, MUTTER, NEPOTE, UHRAHN, VETTER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "nicht nutzbare Pflanze",
      "Antwort": "UNKRAUT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Mediziner",
      "Antwort": "ABBE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "von innen heraus, aus eigener Kraft",
      "Antwort": "AUTOGEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Baltikumbewohner",
      "Antwort": "ESTE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Übungsstück (Musik)",
      "Antwort": "ETUEDE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Truthenne",
      "Antwort": "PUTE, TRUTE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Einwand",
      "Antwort": "ABER, DOCH, ODER, VETO, EINREDE, EINWURF, PROTEST"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "französisch: eine",
      "Antwort": "UNE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Behörde, Dienststelle (Mehrzahl)",
      "Antwort": "AEMTER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Buchherausgeber",
      "Antwort": "EDITOR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "wagemutig, beherzt",
      "Antwort": "KUEHN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Strom in Ostsibirien",
      "Antwort": "AMUR, JANA, LENA, LENO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Rabenvogel",
      "Antwort": "AEGIR, DOHLE, GRAJA, MOEWE, OSCHE, RAKEN, ALSTER, DOHLEN, ELSTER, HAEHER, KRAEHE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "norwegischer Dichter",
      "Antwort": "LIE, MOE, AASEN, GRIEG, IBSEN, UNSET, VINJE, AANRUD, BOYSON, HAMSUN, JAEGER, NILSEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zimmerfolge im Hotel",
      "Antwort": "SUITE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "große Ansiedlung",
      "Antwort": "STADT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "aufwärts, nach oben",
      "Antwort": "EMPOR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "besonders, außerdem",
      "Antwort": "EXTRA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zeugnisnote",
      "Antwort": "DREI, EINS, RITE, VIER, ZWEI, FUENF, SECHS, DREIER, EINSER, ZENSUR, ZWEIER, SEHRGUT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Anpflanzung",
      "Antwort": "ACKER, ANBAU, ZUBAU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Rednerpult für Karnevalisten",
      "Antwort": "BUETT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Glücksvertrag",
      "Antwort": "WETTE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wohlgeschmack",
      "Antwort": "AROMA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "von besonderem Reiz",
      "Antwort": "APART"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schoßhund",
      "Antwort": "MOPS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Knabe",
      "Antwort": "BOY, BUB, BUBE, KERL, KIND, SOHN, JUNGE, PIMPF, WICHT, BENGEL, GARCON, JUGEND"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "tierisches Milchorgan",
      "Antwort": "EUTER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Form des Sauerstoffs",
      "Antwort": "OZON"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Rom in der Landessprache",
      "Antwort": "ROMA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "scherzhaft: Kino",
      "Antwort": "KINTOPP"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Soldatenlohn",
      "Antwort": "SOLD, WEHRSOLD"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Singstimme",
      "Antwort": "ALT, BASS, SOPRAN, STIMME, BARITON"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "zurück",
      "Antwort": "HEIMZU, RETOUR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Teil des Wagens",
      "Antwort": "ACHSE, RUNGE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Teil des Telefons",
      "Antwort": "GABEL, KABEL, HOERER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Laubbaum",
      "Antwort": "ACER, AGBA, AKEE, ALBA, IPER, ULME, URLE, BUCHS, ELLER, FAGUS, MALUS, MANGO, ULMUS, ABELBAUM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stadt in der Lüneburger Heide",
      "Antwort": "CELLE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "leichter Schlag",
      "Antwort": "KLAPS, STUBS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Teilgebiet der Medizin",
      "Antwort": "ANATOMIE, UROLOGIE, CHIRURGIE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Norm, Richtschnur",
      "Antwort": "REGEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Modenarr",
      "Antwort": "BEAU, GECK, DANDY, LAFFE, STUTZER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Baustoff",
      "Antwort": "BIMS, FILZ, GIPS, GLAS, HOLZ, KALK, LEHM, EISEN, SPEIS, STAHL, STEIN, STROH, STUCK, BASALT, GRANIT, MARMOR, SPLITT, ZIEGEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "tiefes Bedauern",
      "Antwort": "REUE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Widerhall",
      "Antwort": "ECHO, HALO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Abstreitender",
      "Antwort": "LEUGNER, LUEGNER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Entwicklungsrichtung",
      "Antwort": "TREND, ABSICHT, NEIGUNG, TENDENZ"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "flüchtiger Augenblick",
      "Antwort": "NU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kellner",
      "Antwort": "OBER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zeichen für Nickel",
      "Antwort": "NI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Null (beim Roulett)",
      "Antwort": "ZERO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zeichen für Neon",
      "Antwort": "NE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Irland in der Landessprache",
      "Antwort": "EIRE, ERIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Teil der Uhr",
      "Antwort": "ANKER, FEDER, KRONE, UNRUH, HAMMER, PENDEL, RETARD, UNRUHE, ZEIGER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schluss",
      "Antwort": "AMEN, ENDE, FINE, HALT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "polnische Stadt an der Oder",
      "Antwort": "BRIEG, BRZEG, BRESLAU, GRYFINO, NOWASOL, SLUBICE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Lenkvorrichtung",
      "Antwort": "LENKER, STEUER, VOLANT, STEUERRAD, STEUERUNG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "oberitalienische Stadt",
      "Antwort": "CESENA, FAENZA, GEMONA, LIMONE, MANTUA, BASSANO, BOLOGNA, CAVAION, CREMONA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Arzneimittelform",
      "Antwort": "CREME, PILLE, SALBE, SIRUP, SPRAY, MIXTUR, PULVER, TABLETTE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Erfindungsgabe",
      "Antwort": "ERFINDERGEIST, IDEENREICHTUM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schwerathlet",
      "Antwort": "BOXER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "englisch: eins",
      "Antwort": "ONE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fahrgast",
      "Antwort": "INSASSE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ein Ganzes",
      "Antwort": "EINTEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "westliches Bündnis",
      "Antwort": "NATO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Matrosengepäck",
      "Antwort": "SEESACK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Bestand",
      "Antwort": "IST, FUNDUS, GUETER, SCHATZ, STATUS, VORRAT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Sprossenstiege",
      "Antwort": "LEITER, TREPPE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Metallstrang",
      "Antwort": "DRAHT, GLEIS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Verbindungsstelle, Ritze",
      "Antwort": "FUGE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "laut und dumpf tönen, hallen",
      "Antwort": "DONNERN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Postsendung",
      "Antwort": "BRIEF, KARTE, PAKET"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Thailänder",
      "Antwort": "SIAMESE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Reise, Ausflug",
      "Antwort": "FAHRT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "durchdringend, scharf",
      "Antwort": "BEISSEND"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wasserstandsmesser",
      "Antwort": "PEGEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schultertuch",
      "Antwort": "FICHU, SCHAL, STOLA, VELUM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Sportwette",
      "Antwort": "TOTO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "poetisch: Wäldchen",
      "Antwort": "HAIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wiederholung (Musik)",
      "Antwort": "REPRISE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "schüchtern",
      "Antwort": "DASIG, KLEIN, SCHEU, TIMID, ACHTSAM, BESORGT, GEHEMMT, ZAGHAFT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Scherflein",
      "Antwort": "ABGABE, ANTEIL, BETRAG, OBOLUS, OBULUS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "bewusst falsche Aussage",
      "Antwort": "LUEGE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "weibliches Haustier",
      "Antwort": "KUH, REN, SAU, FAEHE, GEISS, HENNE, KATZE, MERDE, SCHAF, HUENDIN, MAEUSIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Nutzland, Acker und Wiesen",
      "Antwort": "FLUR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Unteroffizier",
      "Antwort": "KORPORAL, LEUTNANT, SERGEANT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "mit dem Besen reinigen",
      "Antwort": "FEGEN, KEHREN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schicksalsgöttin",
      "Antwort": "DUENA, IDISI, KARTA, KEREN, PARZE, TYCHE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schmuckform",
      "Antwort": "ROSETTE, UCHATON"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Geschäftsinhaber",
      "Antwort": "BOSS, CHEF"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "sagenhafte Insel",
      "Antwort": "THULA, THULE, ATLANTIS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Strafe, Schadenersatz",
      "Antwort": "BUSSE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "belgischer Autor",
      "Antwort": "SIMENON"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "besitzanzeigendes Fürwort",
      "Antwort": "DEIN, EUER, EURE, FUER, IHRE, IHRS, SEIN, EUREM, EUREN, EURES, IHNEN, IHREM, IHREN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "niedersächsischer Hafen",
      "Antwort": "BRAKE, DORUM, EMDEN, JUIST, VAREL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "sumpfiger, kleiner Teich",
      "Antwort": "TUEMPEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Trübung der Luft",
      "Antwort": "DUNST"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Landschaft in Tansania",
      "Antwort": "USAMBARA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Veterinär",
      "Antwort": "ROSSARZT, TIERARZT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "zerdrücken (Kleid, Papier)",
      "Antwort": "KNITTERN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "unzufriedener Mensch",
      "Antwort": "HADERER, MURRKOPF, NOERGLER, QUENGLER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "italienische Stadt (Wein)",
      "Antwort": "ASTI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Herstellung von Büchern",
      "Antwort": "DRUCK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schilf, Röhricht",
      "Antwort": "REET, RIED, RIET"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Himmelskörper (Mehrzahl)",
      "Antwort": "SONNEN, STERNE, KOMETEN, METEORE, GESTIRNE, PLANETEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Staat in Westafrika",
      "Antwort": "MALI, TOGO, CONGO, GABON, GABUN, GHANA, KONGO, NIGER, ANGOLA, BISSAU, GAMBIA, GUINEA, DAHOMEY, LIBERIA, NAMIBIA, NIGERIA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "halblang (Kleidung)",
      "Antwort": "MIDI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Glücksspiel",
      "Antwort": "BELLE, BINGO, BLUFF, CRAPS, POKER, WETTE, BADUGI, BRELAN, DAISIU, FANTAN, REDDOG, BACCARAT, BAKKARAT, FAERBELN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "aus einer Gefahr befreien",
      "Antwort": "RETTEN, ERRETTEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "berittener Polizist der USA",
      "Antwort": "RANGER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Teilstrecke",
      "Antwort": "ETAPPE, STUECK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "vordringlich",
      "Antwort": "AKUT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fluss zum Rhein aus der Eifel",
      "Antwort": "ERFT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "sauber",
      "Antwort": "EDEL, FAIR, NETT, REIN, ADRETT, GESUND, LAUTER, LESBAR, STERIL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fußhebel, Tretkurbel",
      "Antwort": "PEDAL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "österreichische Stadt in Osttirol",
      "Antwort": "LIENZ"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Grabgewölbe",
      "Antwort": "GRUFT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Abschiedsgruß",
      "Antwort": "ADDIO, ADIEU, ADIOS, VALET, BYEBYE, TSCHAU, TSCHOE, FAREWELL, LEBEWOHL, TSCHUESS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "italienisch: ja",
      "Antwort": "SI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Furche",
      "Antwort": "FUGE, NUTE, RITZ, FALTE, KERBE, MULDE, RIEFE, RILLE, RITZE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stockwerk",
      "Antwort": "ETAGE, STOCK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kartenspiel",
      "Antwort": "BETE, BRAG, CEGO, FIPS, KUKU, PICO, SKAT, DUDAK, DURAK, KNACK, MACAO, MAKAO, PEDRO, DILOTI, ELFERN, GEMSCH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Bühnenauftritt",
      "Antwort": "CAMEO, SCENE, SZENE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gesellschaftsinsel",
      "Antwort": "MANUAE, MOOREA, SCILLY, TAHITI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Italienische Stadt an der Nera",
      "Antwort": "NARNI, TERNI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Pelzart",
      "Antwort": "FUCHS, ILTIS, IRBIS, KOALA, LUCHS, OTTER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "lieferbar",
      "Antwort": "VORHANDEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Weise, Gewohnheit",
      "Antwort": "ART"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "gemein, niederträchtig",
      "Antwort": "PERFID"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "immer, zu jeder Zeit",
      "Antwort": "STETS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kerbtier",
      "Antwort": "AMEISE, BREMSE, DROHNE, GRILLE, SPINNE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "schottischer Stammesverband",
      "Antwort": "CLAN, KLAN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "altägyptischer Königstitel",
      "Antwort": "PHARAO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Amts-, Geschäftsbereich",
      "Antwort": "RESSORT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Anerkennung aussprechen",
      "Antwort": "DANKEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Teil des Baumes",
      "Antwort": "BLATT, BORKE, GABEL, KRONE, RINDE, ZWEIG, GEAEST, WIPFEL, WURZEL, ZWIEGE, ASTWERK, KNORREN, AESTCHEN, ASTGABEL, BLAETTER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "einen Brand bekämpfen",
      "Antwort": "LOESCHEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "deutsche Anrede",
      "Antwort": "FRAU, HERR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Sport: das Passieren der Ziellinie",
      "Antwort": "EINLAUF"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "von vorn",
      "Antwort": "FRONTAL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Beifallsruf",
      "Antwort": "BRAVO, CHEER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Heringsfisch",
      "Antwort": "ALSE, SHAD, MAKRELE, SARDINE, SPROTTE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "altindischer Gott",
      "Antwort": "BRAMI, INDRA, SURJA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "nordischer Hirsch",
      "Antwort": "ELK, REN, ELCH, ELEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ableugnen",
      "Antwort": "ABSTREITEN, BESTREITEN, DEMENTIEREN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "diebischer Vogel",
      "Antwort": "ELSTER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "italienische Stadt in der Toskana",
      "Antwort": "CALCI, LUCCA, MASSA, SIENA, AREZZO, CHIUSI, EMPOLI, PIENZA, FIESOLE, FLORENZ"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Operette von Nico Dostal",
      "Antwort": "CLIVIA, MANINA, MONIKA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "südfranzösische Stadt",
      "Antwort": "AGDE, AGEN, ALBI, ALES, AUCH, AXAT, SETE, AGOUT, ARLES, DIJON, NIMES, NIORT, VICHI, CAHORS, FREJUS, GRASSE, HYERES, ORANGE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "rügender Beurteiler",
      "Antwort": "TADLER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Vorbedeutung",
      "Antwort": "OMEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wikinger, Nordgermane",
      "Antwort": "NORMANNE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stadt am Ems-Jade-Kanal",
      "Antwort": "AURICH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "europäisches Meer",
      "Antwort": "OSTSEE, NORDSEE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "asiatisches Volk",
      "Antwort": "AZ"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Ehemann",
      "Antwort": "ALTER, EPOSO, EPOUX, GATTE, MUSCH, GEMAHL, MANZEL, MARITO, TYRANN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "englische Schulstadt",
      "Antwort": "ETON"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Unterkunft, Wohnung",
      "Antwort": "LOGIS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "schwedische Insel",
      "Antwort": "VEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stille",
      "Antwort": "RUHE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Anständigkeit",
      "Antwort": "TREUE, ANSTAND, FAIRNESS, LAUTERKEIT, REDLICHKEIT, RICHTIGKEIT, RECHTSCHAFFENHEIT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Reiterschau der Cowboys",
      "Antwort": "RODEO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Behauptung, Leitsatz",
      "Antwort": "THESE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "augenblickliche Stimmung",
      "Antwort": "LAUNE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Göttertrank, Blütensaft",
      "Antwort": "NEKTAR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zimmerwinkel",
      "Antwort": "ECKE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "asiatischer Halbesel",
      "Antwort": "KIANG, KULAN, PIPAL, BANJAN, DONKEY, ONAGER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Sohn des Zeus",
      "Antwort": "APOLL, ARKAS, LINOS, MINOS, CASTOR, IASION, KASTOR, POLLUX, ZETHOS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Brettspielfigur",
      "Antwort": "KEGEL, SPYRI, STEIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gesteinsart",
      "Antwort": "AKMIT, APLIT, BASIT, DACIT, FLINZ, QUARZ"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "von geringer Größe",
      "Antwort": "KLEIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stacheltier",
      "Antwort": "IGEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "brav, höflich",
      "Antwort": "ARTIG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Teil des Skeletts",
      "Antwort": "KNOCHEN, SPEICHE, BRUSTKORB"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Rest im Glas",
      "Antwort": "MIEGE, NEIGE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "kurze Jacke",
      "Antwort": "ROCK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "lässig, ungezwungen",
      "Antwort": "LEGER, SALOPP"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "in Hinsicht auf",
      "Antwort": "BEZUEGLICH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "altisländisches Schrifttum",
      "Antwort": "EDDA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Ring, Spielzeug",
      "Antwort": "REIF"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Beweisstück, Quittung",
      "Antwort": "BELEG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "biblische Männergestalt",
      "Antwort": "ABAN, ABEL, ADAM, ARON, ESRA, MESA, SAUL, ASSER, ENOCH, HADAD, ISAAK, JUBAL, LABAN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stuhlteil",
      "Antwort": "BEIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "deutscher Sänger (Peter)",
      "Antwort": "ANDERS, KRAUSS, MAFFAY, MAFFEY, PETREL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Anzeichen von Müdigkeit",
      "Antwort": "GAEHNEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "oberitalienischer Fluss",
      "Antwort": "ADIGE, ETSCH, PIAVE, BRENTA, ISONZO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gesellschaftstanz",
      "Antwort": "FOX"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Körperglied",
      "Antwort": "ARM, ZEH, ARME, BEIN, FUSS, HAND, KNIE, ZEHE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Maschine für Erdarbeiten",
      "Antwort": "BAGGER, SCAPER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "scherzhaft: Gespür, Nase",
      "Antwort": "RIECHER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Tochter des Agamemnon",
      "Antwort": "ELEKTRA, IPHIGENIE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "italienische Insel",
      "Antwort": "BELLA, CAPRI, ISOLA, PONZA, GIGLIO, ISCHIA, LIPARI, SALINA, USTICA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Beständigkeit",
      "Antwort": "DAUER, STETE, TREUE, WILLE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Tierpfote",
      "Antwort": "KLAUE, TALPE, TATZE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Turngerät",
      "Antwort": "BALL, BANN, BOCK, RECK, REIF, RING, SEIL, KEULE, MATTE, PFERD, RECKS, RINGE, BELUGA, LEITER, LIMOSA, REIFEN, TRAPEZ, EXPANDER, QUERBAUM, RHOENRAD"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Metallschlinge",
      "Antwort": "OESE, MASCHE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "kleine Feuererscheinung",
      "Antwort": "FUNKE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Vorhaben, Absicht",
      "Antwort": "PLAN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt von Vietnam",
      "Antwort": "HANOI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "heiter, vergnügt",
      "Antwort": "FROH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ungeordnet",
      "Antwort": "BUNT, WIRR, KRAUS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "südamerikanische Währung",
      "Antwort": "PESO, REAL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "exakt, pünktlich",
      "Antwort": "GENAU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Riechmittel tierischer Herkunft",
      "Antwort": "AMBER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Nählinie",
      "Antwort": "NAHR, NAHT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gnom, Knirps",
      "Antwort": "ZWERG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "griechischer Liebesgott",
      "Antwort": "EROS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "befestigter Stadtteil in russischen Städten",
      "Antwort": "KREML"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Nähgerät",
      "Antwort": "NADEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Speisenfolge",
      "Antwort": "MENU, DENUE, MENUE, SERIE, GEDECK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "übertrieben sparen",
      "Antwort": "GEIZEN, KNAUSERN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ungebunden",
      "Antwort": "FREI, LOSE, WILD"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wertloses",
      "Antwort": "ABFALL, ABFUHR, GAMMEL, NICHTS, RAMSCH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Benennung",
      "Antwort": "NAME, WORT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ermächtigt, berechtigt",
      "Antwort": "BEFUGT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Waldland in Feld verwandeln",
      "Antwort": "RODEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Ureinwohner Neuseelands",
      "Antwort": "MAORI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fruchtbrei",
      "Antwort": "JAM, MUS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schilderung friedlichen Lebens",
      "Antwort": "IDYLLE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "nicht rechtzeitig",
      "Antwort": "SPAET"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Eingang",
      "Antwort": "FLUR, TUER, BEGINN, ENTREE, PFORTE, PORTAL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "wirr, verworren",
      "Antwort": "KONFUS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Eile, überstürztes Drängen",
      "Antwort": "HAST, HETZE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Paradies",
      "Antwort": "ADAN, EDEN, OASE, DJANNA, DORADO, HIMMEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "zusätzliche Bezeichnung einer Person",
      "Antwort": "BEINAME"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "deutscher Schauspieler (Harald)",
      "Antwort": "LEIPNITZ"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ausgezeichnet",
      "Antwort": "BRAVO, DUFTE, EINSA, FAMOS, IDEAL, KLASS, BRILLAND, BRILLANT, TIPPTOPP"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Beamtentitel",
      "Antwort": "ADJUNKT, AMTMANN, AMTSRAT, ATTACHE, ASSISTENT, KONREKTOR, PROFESSOR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schiffszubehör",
      "Antwort": "ANKER, RUDER, SEGEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Behälter für Heizstoff",
      "Antwort": "TANK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Geheimschriftenschlüssel",
      "Antwort": "CODE, KODE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Altertum",
      "Antwort": "ANTIKE, URZEIT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "alleiniges Vorrecht",
      "Antwort": "MONOPOL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Lustspiel",
      "Antwort": "FARCE, POSSE, BURLESKE, KLAMOTTE, KOMOEDIE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "hohe Spielkarten",
      "Antwort": "ASSE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Ohren des Jagdhundes",
      "Antwort": "BEHANG, BEHAENGE, GEHAENGE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "etwas Neues",
      "Antwort": "NOVUM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Volltreffer beim Toto",
      "Antwort": "ELFER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Geldinstitut",
      "Antwort": "BANK, BANKHAUS, GIROBANK, HAUSBANK, GIROKASSE, NOTENBANK, VOLKSBANK, POSTGIROAMT, ZENTRALBANK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptschlagader",
      "Antwort": "AORTA, ARTERIE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Frauenname",
      "Antwort": "AK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zone von zwölf Sternbildern",
      "Antwort": "TIERKREIS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Mahlzeit, Nahrung",
      "Antwort": "DINER, ESSEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Teil eines Zeitmessers",
      "Antwort": "UHRGLAS, UHRWERK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schiff der Argonauten",
      "Antwort": "ARGO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gefängnis (umgangssprachlich)",
      "Antwort": "BAU, KNAST, KITTCHEN, SINGSING"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Ergänzung, Nachtrag",
      "Antwort": "ZUSATZ, EINSCHUB, NACHTRAG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "südamerikanischer Indianer",
      "Antwort": "INDIO, KARIBE, KIOWAS, KREOLE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "spenden",
      "Antwort": "ABGEBEN, DOTIERE, STIFTEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "verächtlich: Mann",
      "Antwort": "KERL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "französischer Maler",
      "Antwort": "ALAUX, BIARD, COROT, DEGAS, KUPKA, VOUET, BALLOT, BAUDRY, LATOUR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kirchengalerie",
      "Antwort": "EMPORE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Würdigung",
      "Antwort": "LOB, EHRUNG, LOBREDE, NACHRUF, RESPEKT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Dichter",
      "Antwort": "BAIK, BALL, BING, BIRO, CEPL, ENKE, EVRU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Absage",
      "Antwort": "KORB, NEIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Siebensachen, Plunder",
      "Antwort": "KRAM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Baldriangewächs",
      "Antwort": "FEDIA, NARDE, SPEIK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Lust, Reiz",
      "Antwort": "KITZEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stadt in der Lausitz",
      "Antwort": "BENAU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "verblüffend, überraschend",
      "Antwort": "STUPEND"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "schrill schreien",
      "Antwort": "GELLEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Barzahlung (englisch)",
      "Antwort": "CASH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "linker Nebenfluss der Fulda",
      "Antwort": "AARE, AHNE, AULA, EDER, ESPE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Strom in die Rigaer Bucht",
      "Antwort": "DUENA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "erzürnt",
      "Antwort": "BOESE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "zerplatzen",
      "Antwort": "BERSTEN, BRECHEN, KNALLEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Holzfarbe",
      "Antwort": "BEIZE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "netzartiges Gewebe",
      "Antwort": "GASE, GAZE, FILET, LACIS, TUELL, TWILL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gewässer ",
      "Antwort": "BAI, SEE, BUSEN, LACHE, MEERE, PRIEL, STROM, TEICH, FLUESSE, PAZIFIK, PFUETZE, STROEME"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Viehhüter",
      "Antwort": "HIRT, PEON, SENN, HEGER, HIRTE, ALMHIRTE, KUHHIRTE, SCHAEFER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "russischer Maler",
      "Antwort": "KAREW, KLJUN, KORIN, PEROW, POPOW, UTKIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Regenbogenhaut des Auges",
      "Antwort": "IRIS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Tränen vergießen",
      "Antwort": "HEULEN, WEINEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ein Küchengerät",
      "Antwort": "REIBEISEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Offiziersrang",
      "Antwort": "MAJOR, OBERST, ADMIRAL, GENERAL, KAPITAEN, LEUTNANT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "feinkörnig",
      "Antwort": "MEHLIG, SANDIG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Handelsware",
      "Antwort": "GUETER, ARTIKEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "orientalische Kopfbedeckung",
      "Antwort": "FES, FEZ, TURBAN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Futterpflanze",
      "Antwort": "BETE, GRAS, HANF, KLEE, LEIN, MAIS, RAPS, ATAYA, ESPER, HAFER, MELDE, SERRA, SPARK, GERSTE, LUPINE, MUCUNA, RUNKEL, ALFALFA, GIERSCH, MELASSE, ROTKLEE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Roman von Anet",
      "Antwort": "ARIANE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "seltenes Erdmetall",
      "Antwort": "BOR, CER, ZER, HOLMIUM, LANTHAN, TERBIUM, YTTRIUM, EUROPIUM, LUTETIUM, PRASEODYM, YTTERBIUM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stadt am Rhein",
      "Antwort": "BEUEL, KOELN, STEIN, UNKEL, WESEL, BINGEN, FILSEN, HONNEF, KAPPEL, WALSUM, BOPPARD, HOMBERG, KOBLENZ, KREFELD"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Roman von Zola",
      "Antwort": "NANA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Farbüberzug",
      "Antwort": "LACK, ANSTRICH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Raumtonverfahren (Kurzwort)",
      "Antwort": "STEREO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wacholderbranntwein",
      "Antwort": "GIN, GENEVER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "griechische Siegesgöttin",
      "Antwort": "NIKE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "bestimmter Artikel",
      "Antwort": "DAS, DEM, DEN, DER, DES, DIE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Lotterieanteilschein",
      "Antwort": "LOS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fräsrinne",
      "Antwort": "NUTE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Quellfluss der Weser",
      "Antwort": "FULDA, MUNDE, WERRA, WESER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schicht der internationalen Gesellschaft",
      "Antwort": "JETSET"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Nachtvogel",
      "Antwort": "EULE, KAUZ, UHUS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Einladender",
      "Antwort": "GASTGEBER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "bedenklich, verdächtig",
      "Antwort": "KITZLIG, OMINOES, PREKAER, SUSPEKT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Südostasien-Pakt",
      "Antwort": "SEATO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "zur Gewohnheit geworden",
      "Antwort": "EINGEFLEISCHT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Brutstätte",
      "Antwort": "NEST, NESTBAU, BRUTPLATZ, KEIMZELLE, NISTPLATZ"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Ausdrucksform",
      "Antwort": "EKEL, FORM, PFUI, STIL, TAKT, WORT, AUSDRUCK, GEPRAEGE, PRAEGUNG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Dynastie im alten Peru",
      "Antwort": "INKA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wasserfahrzeug",
      "Antwort": "ASKE, BARK, BOOT, KAHN, KANU, PRAU, SLOP, BRIGG, JOLLE, KOGGE, PRAHM, SKIFF, ZILLE, FAEHRE, FELUKE, SCHIFF, SCHLUP, SCHUTE, FLUSSKAHN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "römische Göttin",
      "Antwort": "CARNA, COPIA, DAMIA, EPONA, MINER, PARCE, EGERIA, LEVANA, LIBERA, MONETA, TUTELA, BELLONA, BONADEA, FERONIA, FORTUNA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "spanischer Fluss",
      "Antwort": "EO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schriftreihe",
      "Antwort": "FOLGE, ZEILE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Naturtrieb",
      "Antwort": "INSTINKT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "größter Strom Hinterindiens",
      "Antwort": "MEKONG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kohleprodukt",
      "Antwort": "BUNA, GRUS, KOKS, PECH, TEER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Körnerfrucht",
      "Antwort": "MAIS, RAPS, REIS, AMARANTH, GETREIDE, WILDREIS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ostfriesische Insel",
      "Antwort": "AMRUM, BUISE, JUIST, BORKUM, MELLUM, BALTRUM, MEMMERT, NEUWERK, LANGEOOG, NORDENEY"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Todeslauf",
      "Antwort": "AMOK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Frisiergerät",
      "Antwort": "KAMM, BUERSTE, STIELKAMM, BRENNSCHERE, GLAETTEISEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "frühere italienische Währungseinheit",
      "Antwort": "LIRA, LIRE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "feierliche Zeremonie",
      "Antwort": "WEIHE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wüstenei",
      "Antwort": "OASE, OEDE, EINOEDE, WILDNIS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Elan, Schwung",
      "Antwort": "PEP, VERVE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "norditalienische Stadt am Po",
      "Antwort": "PAVIA, TURIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "junger Pflanzenspross",
      "Antwort": "TRIEB"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Artigkeit, Schmeichelei",
      "Antwort": "KOMPLIMENT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Waffenlager",
      "Antwort": "ARSENAL, MAGAZIN, ZEUGAMT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "adlig, vornehm",
      "Antwort": "NOBEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Persönlichkeitsbild",
      "Antwort": "IMAGE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "große Flüsse",
      "Antwort": "STROEME"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Handdreschgerät",
      "Antwort": "BEUGEL, FLEGEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gebäudeteil, Zimmer",
      "Antwort": "RAUM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Insel an der Küste Ostafrikas",
      "Antwort": "SANSIBAR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Heidekrautgewächs",
      "Antwort": "ERICA, ERIKA, MYHRE, PORST, AZALEA, AZALEE, AZALIE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "nicht sichtbar",
      "Antwort": "GETARNT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gewinner",
      "Antwort": "BESTER, ERSTER, SIEGER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "tückisches Vorgehen",
      "Antwort": "RAENKE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Verpflegungssatz",
      "Antwort": "RATION"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Besitz, Vermögen",
      "Antwort": "GELD, HABE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "schmutzige Flüssigkeit",
      "Antwort": "BRUEHE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "zeitgemäß (englisch)",
      "Antwort": "UPTODATE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Waldvogel",
      "Antwort": "HAEHER, SPECHT, AUERHAHN, AUERHUHN, SCHNEPFE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "übrig geblieben",
      "Antwort": "RESTLICH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "blühende Pflanze",
      "Antwort": "BLUME"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kinderfahrzeug",
      "Antwort": "DREIRAD, FAHRRAD, KETTCAR, LAUFRAD"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Ruderkriegsschiff",
      "Antwort": "GALEERE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ein Nest bauen und brüten",
      "Antwort": "NISTEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "dehnbares Gewebe",
      "Antwort": "ELASTAN, ELASTIK, SPANDEX, STRETCH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Laubbäume",
      "Antwort": "ELLER, ERLEN, ESPEN, HASEL, ULMEN, BIRKEN, BUCHEN, EICHEL, ELLERN, WEIDEN, AKAZIEN, PAPPELN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstrom Vorderasiens",
      "Antwort": "INDUS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Tagesabschnitt",
      "Antwort": "ABEND, NACHT, ABENDE, FRUEHE, MITTAG, MORGEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Geliebte Karls des VII.",
      "Antwort": "SOREL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Flachsfaser, Gewebeart",
      "Antwort": "LEINEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Junge, Bube",
      "Antwort": "KNABE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stadt im Ruhrgebiet",
      "Antwort": "HAMM, MARL, UNNA, WERL, ABEND, ESSEN, HAGEN, KAMEN, MOERS, WESEL, HERTEN, LUENEN, MASSEN, NEHEIM, WETTER, BOCHOLT, BOTTROP, DATTELN, HERBEDE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "arbeitsfreier Tag",
      "Antwort": "FEIERTAG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gesottenes",
      "Antwort": "SUD"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "dicklich und bequem",
      "Antwort": "BEHAEBIG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "unhöflicher Mensch",
      "Antwort": "GROBIAN, STIESEL, STOFFEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fischfett",
      "Antwort": "TRAN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Rücken und Deckel des Buches",
      "Antwort": "EINBAND"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Ausspritzmundstück",
      "Antwort": "DUESE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schleswig-holsteinische Stadt",
      "Antwort": "EUTIN, HEIDE, HUSUM, ITZEHOE, KAPPELN, LENSAHN, LUEBECK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "akademischer Titel (Abkürzung)",
      "Antwort": "JUR, DIPL, PROF"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gattin",
      "Antwort": "FRAU, EHEFRAU, EHEWEIB, GEMAHLIN, EHEPARTNERIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Sportgröße, bestes Pferd",
      "Antwort": "CRACK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kunstflugfigur",
      "Antwort": "TURN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stadt im südlichen Baden-Württemberg",
      "Antwort": "LOERRACH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ausgedehntes Gastmahl",
      "Antwort": "GELAGE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ein Kind annehmen",
      "Antwort": "ADOPTIEREN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "italienisch: vorwärts",
      "Antwort": "AVANTI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fluss in Westafrika",
      "Antwort": "NIGER, VOLTA, BANDAMA, CALABAR, SENEGAL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "früher",
      "Antwort": "EHER, ERST, MEHR, AELTER, BISHER, DAMALS, EHEDEM, EINMAL, BISLANG, DAMALIG, DAZUMAL, FRUEHER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "französische Halbinsel",
      "Antwort": "BRETAGNE, COTENTIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Europäer",
      "Antwort": "IRE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zeitpunkt, Frist",
      "Antwort": "TERMIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "großes Gästehaus",
      "Antwort": "HOTEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "unverfälscht",
      "Antwort": "ECHT, REIN, WAHR, GENUIN, LAUTER, SCHIER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "vulkanisierter Kautschuk",
      "Antwort": "GUMMI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "unsicher machen",
      "Antwort": "BEIRREN, IRRITIEREN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "innere Gliederung, Aufbau",
      "Antwort": "STRUKTUR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Verhalten in heikler Lage",
      "Antwort": "EIERTANZ"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "französisches Kartenspiel",
      "Antwort": "BASIK, BESIK, PHARO, POKER, RUMMY, TAROK, AMBIGU, BELOTE, BOSTON, GAIGEL, PIQUET"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Luftrolle (Sport)",
      "Antwort": "SALTO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "englisch-amerikanisches Längenmaß",
      "Antwort": "FOOT, INCH, LINK, YARD, ZOLL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Südfrucht",
      "Antwort": "FEIGE, GUAVA, GUAVE, KHAKI, KIWAI, MANGO, CITRUS, DATTEL, JOCOTE, MARULA, ORANGE, ACEROLA, AVOCADO, GUAJAVE, GUAYAVE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "französischer Filmstar",
      "Antwort": "RENO, CANET, DELON, DELPY, GABIN, BARDOT, CLMENT, COURAU, MARAIS, VARTAN, BELMONDO, GIRARDOT, SIGNORET"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Muskel",
      "Antwort": "BEUGER, BIZEPS, KNETEN, TRIZEPS, ABDUKTOR, ABZIEHER, ADDUKTOR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Korridor",
      "Antwort": "EREN, FLUR, GANG, DIELE, FLETZ, HALLE, HAUSFLUR, HAUSGANG, VORPLATZ"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gedenkstätte",
      "Antwort": "DENKMAL, GRABMAL, MAHNMAL, MARTERL, EHRENMAL, FRIEDHOF, MEMORIAL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Teilzahlung",
      "Antwort": "RATE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Früchte einbringen",
      "Antwort": "ERNTEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "rundlich, vollschlank",
      "Antwort": "MOLLIG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "großer und starker Mann",
      "Antwort": "HUENE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kehrreim",
      "Antwort": "REFRAIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Titel arabischer Fürsten",
      "Antwort": "EMIR, OMAN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kaloriengehalt",
      "Antwort": "NAEHRWERT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Tonfall am Satzende",
      "Antwort": "KADENZ"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "früherer österreichischer Adelstitel",
      "Antwort": "EDLE, GRAF, EDLER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Steinspiel",
      "Antwort": "DOMINO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Einfall, Gedanke",
      "Antwort": "IDEE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "italienischer Reibekäse",
      "Antwort": "PARMESAN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gießgefäß",
      "Antwort": "EIMER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Marktbude",
      "Antwort": "STAND"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Bambus, große Gräserart",
      "Antwort": "ROHR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Riese",
      "Antwort": "AEGIR, ARGUS, ATLAS, BULLE, HUENE, TITAN, FAFNER, FAFNIR, FASOLD, GIGANT, HUEHNE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt der Bahamas",
      "Antwort": "NASSAU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "mild, sanft",
      "Antwort": "LIND"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "zuständige Behördenstelle",
      "Antwort": "INSTANZ"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Teil des Schaltgetriebes",
      "Antwort": "GANG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Palmenfrucht",
      "Antwort": "KOKOS, SALAK, BANANE, DATTEL, DATURA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kürbisgewächs",
      "Antwort": "ADOBRA, CAIGUA, KARELA, MELONE, TALOTE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schulfach",
      "Antwort": "ETHIK, KUNST, LESEN, MATHE, MUSIK, SPORT, KOCHEN, LATEIN, NAEHEN, TURNEN, WERKEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Nationalitätszeichen Tunesien",
      "Antwort": "TN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Inseln im Atlantik",
      "Antwort": "AZOREN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Flaumfeder",
      "Antwort": "DUNE, WETI, DAUNE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Luftstromerzeuger",
      "Antwort": "GEBLAESE, BLASEBALG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "manche",
      "Antwort": "EINIGE, WENIGE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "biblischer Prophet",
      "Antwort": "AMOS, ASSA, ELIA, ESRA, HIOB, JONA, OSEE, AHIJA, ELIJA, HULDA, ISAIA, LSAIA, MICHA, ABDIAS, BARUCH, BILEAM, DANIEL, SAMUEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gaststätte",
      "Antwort": "BARS, CAFE, KRUG, BAUDE, BEISL, BEIZE, MESSE, PINTE, STAMP, ABSTEIGE, CAFEHAUS, HAFENBAR, BIERHALLE, BIERLOKAL, GARKUECHE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schmelzüberzug",
      "Antwort": "EMAIL, LASUR, EMAILLE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt von Tibet",
      "Antwort": "LHASA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "regsam und wendig",
      "Antwort": "AGIL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zierstrauch",
      "Antwort": "AUKUBA, CISSUS, CORNUS, JASMIN, KERRIA, ARDISIE, ASTILBE, ROTDORN, SPIRAEE, HIBISCUS, HIBISKUS, OLEANDER, ALPENROSE, BANKSROSE, HELIOTROP"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Sinnbild unzertrennlicher Dreiheit",
      "Antwort": "DREIBLATT, KLEEBLATT, TRINITAET"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Befreiung von Sündenstrafen",
      "Antwort": "ERLOESUNG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schweizer Sagenheld",
      "Antwort": "TELL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptheiligtum des Islam",
      "Antwort": "KAABA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Preisgrenze",
      "Antwort": "LIMIT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Drama von Goethe",
      "Antwort": "EGMONT, STELLA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Dunst über Großstädten",
      "Antwort": "SMOG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "amerikanische Münze",
      "Antwort": "CENT, DIME, PESO, COLON, EAGLE, PESCO, PEXCO, SUCRE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kunstdüngemittel",
      "Antwort": "KALI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kaukasier",
      "Antwort": "ADYGE, ALANE, ASEGA, AWARE, TATAR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "vermuten, für richtig halten",
      "Antwort": "AHNEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Bezirk von Berlin",
      "Antwort": "PANKOW, MARZAHN, SPANDAU, TREPTOW, WEDDING"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Mädchen im Wunderland",
      "Antwort": "ALICE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Grundstoff",
      "Antwort": "METALL, ELEMENT, URSTOFF"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "mittelasiatischer Fürstentitel",
      "Antwort": "CHAN, KHAN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Orgelteil",
      "Antwort": "CLAVIS, MANUAL, PFEIFE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Raumfahrer",
      "Antwort": "BELLA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "erlernte Arbeit",
      "Antwort": "BERUF"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "eingezäuntes Gebiet für Wild",
      "Antwort": "GEHEGE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stimmzettelbehälter",
      "Antwort": "URNE, WAHLURNE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Blütenstandsform",
      "Antwort": "DOLDE, KRONE, RISPE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "altes, wertloses Pferd",
      "Antwort": "GAUL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "von geringer Dicke",
      "Antwort": "DUENN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Lautstärkemaß",
      "Antwort": "PHON, SONE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "kostbar, menschlich vornehm",
      "Antwort": "EDEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "gefährliches Kunststück (Film)",
      "Antwort": "STUNT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kork, Stöpsel",
      "Antwort": "KORKEN, PFROPF, ZAPFEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Teil des Bruches",
      "Antwort": "NENNER, TEILER, DIVISOR, ZAEHLER, DIVIDEND"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ritterlich, höflich",
      "Antwort": "GALANT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "niedersächsische Stadt",
      "Antwort": "BERGE, BRAKE, CELLE, DAMME, EMDEN, ESENS, BRAKEL, GOSLAR, GRONAU, LEHRTE, LETTER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Vogelnest mit Eiern",
      "Antwort": "GELEGE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "plötzliches Anreißen",
      "Antwort": "RISS, RUCK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "durchzeichnen",
      "Antwort": "PAUSEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "russisches Gewässer in Karelien",
      "Antwort": "ONEGASEE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Speisender",
      "Antwort": "ESSER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Küchengefäß",
      "Antwort": "PFANNE, PLATTE, TIEGEL, BACKFORM, KOCHTOPF"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Haremswächter",
      "Antwort": "EUNUCH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Sportkleidung",
      "Antwort": "DRESS, KLUFT, TRICOT, TRIKOT, TURNHEMD, TURNHOSE, TURNZEUG, BADEANZUG, TURNANZUG, TURNSCHUH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "lockern",
      "Antwort": "LOESEN, RASTEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Klosterfrau",
      "Antwort": "NONNE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "überstürzt, eilig",
      "Antwort": "HASTIG, HURTIG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "südeuropäischer Staat",
      "Antwort": "ITALIEN, SERBIEN, SPANIEN, ALBANIEN, KROATIEN, PORTUGAL, BULGARIEN, RUMAENIEN, SLOWENIEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schauspieler",
      "Antwort": "COBA, DEPP, FORD, HOLT, OTTO, ROTH, TODD, ARLEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "leichter Wind",
      "Antwort": "BRISE, HAUCH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ostenglische Grafschaft",
      "Antwort": "LINCOLN, NORFOLK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Bruder des Romulus",
      "Antwort": "REMUS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kloster",
      "Antwort": "ABTEI, STIFT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Verzeichnis der Tage des Jahres",
      "Antwort": "KALENDER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Rundtanz",
      "Antwort": "GALOPP, REIGEN, REIHEN, WALZER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wüsteninsel",
      "Antwort": "OASE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "römischer Liebesgott",
      "Antwort": "AMOR, CUPIDO, KUPIDO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Rassehund",
      "Antwort": "BOXER, DINGO, HUSKY, SLUKI, SPITZ, ULMER, BRIARD, BUHUND, DACKEL, KUVASZ, TSCHIN, BASENJI, KOMODOR, SHELTIE, SLOUGHI, HOVAWART, LABRADOR, MALTESER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zugspitzgewässer",
      "Antwort": "EIBSEE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Farbe",
      "Antwort": "BLEU, FALB, GELB, GOLD, KARO, LACK, ROSA, BEIGE, BEIZE, BLOND, BRAUN, CREME, SIENA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Heilbehandlung",
      "Antwort": "BADEKUR, HEFEKUR, MASSAGE, TRETKUR, DAUERBAD, INFUSION, LIEGEKUR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Beute, Jagdergebnis",
      "Antwort": "FANG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stadt am Niederrhein",
      "Antwort": "BONN, GOCH, REES, ZONS, ALPEN, ISSUM, KLEVE, KOELN, MOERS, NEUSS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "große Türen, Pforten",
      "Antwort": "TORE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Staat in Südostasien",
      "Antwort": "LAAN, LAOS, MYANMAR, VIETNAM, MALAYSIA, SINGAPUR, THAILAND"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Auswanderer",
      "Antwort": "EMIGRANT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Berührungsverbot",
      "Antwort": "TABU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stadt in SW-England",
      "Antwort": "EXETER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Rettungsschiff, Gig",
      "Antwort": "BEIBOOT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Nachlassempfänger",
      "Antwort": "ERBE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "norwegische Hauptstadt",
      "Antwort": "OSLO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "unversehrt",
      "Antwort": "GESUND, INTAKT, INTEGER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zusammentreffen",
      "Antwort": "BEGEGNUNG, KONGRUENT, VERBINDEN, KOLLIDIEREN, KONJUNKTION, UNTERREDUNG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Wundmal",
      "Antwort": "NARBE, WUNDE, STIGMA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gefühl des Bloßgestelltseins",
      "Antwort": "SCHAM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Einspruch",
      "Antwort": "ABER, VETO, EINREDE, EINWAND, EINWURF, PROTEST"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Teil einer Steinfrucht",
      "Antwort": "OBSTKERN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fluss zur Saale",
      "Antwort": "BODE, ORLA, RODA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Blutgefäß",
      "Antwort": "ADER, VENE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Haushaltsplan",
      "Antwort": "ETAT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stadt im Schwarzwald",
      "Antwort": "CALW, LAHR, BUEHL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gewichtseinheit (Kurzwort)",
      "Antwort": "DEKA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Riese und Wächter (griechische Sage)",
      "Antwort": "ARGUS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Loch, fehlendes Stück",
      "Antwort": "LUECKE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Schutzstoffe einspritzen",
      "Antwort": "EINIMPFEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Vererbungslehre",
      "Antwort": "EUGENIK, GENETIK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kehrgerät",
      "Antwort": "BESEN, FEGER, HAARBESEN, LAUBBESEN, REISBESEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "amerikanischer Filmkomiker",
      "Antwort": "ALLEN, BROWN, HARDY, LEWIS, LLOYD, ABBOTT, KEATON, LAUREL, MARTIN, MURPHY"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Seemannsruf",
      "Antwort": "AHOI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Skitorlauf",
      "Antwort": "SLALOM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Erzengel",
      "Antwort": "URIEL, GABRIEL, MICHAEL, RAPHAEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "eine Behörde",
      "Antwort": "BAUAMT, FUNDAMT, KREISAMT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Indischer geistlicher Lehrer",
      "Antwort": "GURU, YOGI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Abkürzung für das ist",
      "Antwort": "DI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fasanenvogel",
      "Antwort": "PFAU, KRANICH, PEROHAN, REBHUHN, WACHTEL, AUERHUHN, BIRKHUHN, PERLHUHN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "kleines Wirtshaus, Schenke",
      "Antwort": "PINTE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Vorsilbe: Leben",
      "Antwort": "BIO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "kleine Brücke",
      "Antwort": "STEG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Kuhantilope",
      "Antwort": "ETA, GNU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "mit Nahrung versorgen",
      "Antwort": "NAEHREN, FUETTERN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gelehrtensprache",
      "Antwort": "LATEIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Klavierjazz",
      "Antwort": "RAG, RAGTIME"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Lanzenreiter",
      "Antwort": "ULAN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "viel und mühsam arbeiten",
      "Antwort": "ACKERN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stadt auf Kreta",
      "Antwort": "KANEA, MALIA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "europäischer Staat",
      "Antwort": "IRLAND, ISLAND, KOSOVO, MOLDAU, ZYPERN, ITALIEN, LITAUEN, UKRAINE, VATIKAN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Drüsenabsonderung",
      "Antwort": "EXKRET, INKRET, SEKRET, SEKRETE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Initiator",
      "Antwort": "ANREGER, ERREGER, FAISEUR, URHEBER, ANFAENGER, ANSTIFTER, GESTALTER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Verkehrsmittel",
      "Antwort": "AUTOBUS, CITYBUS, DAMPFER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "öffnen, zugänglich machen",
      "Antwort": "AUFTUN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Stadt an der Weißen Elster",
      "Antwort": "AZEL, GERA, LANA, ADORF, ADULA, BERGA, HALLE, PEGAU, ZEISS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Klingel",
      "Antwort": "BIMMEL, GLOCKE, SCHELLE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Bezirk, Gegend",
      "Antwort": "REGION"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Sammlung von Schriftstücken",
      "Antwort": "AKTE, AKTEI, AKTEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Burg in der Eifel",
      "Antwort": "ELTZ, SALM"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "himmelblaue Farbe",
      "Antwort": "AZUR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "fleißiges Insekt",
      "Antwort": "AMEISE, HUMMEL, TERMITE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Übervorteilung im Preis",
      "Antwort": "NEPP"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Erfrischungsgetränk",
      "Antwort": "BIER, COKE, COLA, KOLA, LIMO, MOST, SODA, AGREST, BRAUSE, EISTEE, FRAPPE, FRISCO, CLUBMATE, LIMONADE, MALZBIER, APFELSAFT, GINGERALE, LONGDRINK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "törichte Frau",
      "Antwort": "NAERRIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "navigieren",
      "Antwort": "STEUERN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Defekt bei einer Feuerwaffe",
      "Antwort": "LADEHEMMUNG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Speisenwürze",
      "Antwort": "SALZ"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gegner",
      "Antwort": "FEIND"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Herrendienst, Pflichtarbeit",
      "Antwort": "FRON"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Angriff",
      "Antwort": "EINFALL, KOLLAPS, PHAIANX, PHALANX"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "liegen, entspannen",
      "Antwort": "RUHEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zeichen für Lithium",
      "Antwort": "LI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Apfelsorte",
      "Antwort": "AKEROE, ANGOLD, CAROLA, CAUDLE, UNDINE, AURALIA, CALVILL, FILIPPA, KALVILL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Gebührenliste",
      "Antwort": "TARIF"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Lederhandwerker",
      "Antwort": "SATTLER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Ostwind der Tropen",
      "Antwort": "PASSAT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Blattgemüse",
      "Antwort": "KOHL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "kleine, bunte Spielkugel",
      "Antwort": "MURMEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "kurze Begebenheit",
      "Antwort": "EPISODE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "römischer Staatsmann (Marcus)",
      "Antwort": "ANTONIUS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "würzige Flüssigkeit",
      "Antwort": "BRUEHE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "kleinlich",
      "Antwort": "ENGHERZIG, KNAUSERIG, KNICKERIG, BANAUSISCH, BERECHNEND, ENGSTRINIG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "nie, niemals",
      "Antwort": "NIMMER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "emporklettern (Pflanzen)",
      "Antwort": "RANKEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Edelgas",
      "Antwort": "NEON, ARGON, BUTAN, NITON, RADON, XENON"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Landschaft am Jordan",
      "Antwort": "MOAB"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Möbelstück",
      "Antwort": "COUCH, DIWAN, LIEGE, REGAL, SPIND, WIEGE, BUEFETT, BUEFFET, EHEBETT, ESSBANK, BETTBANK, FUSSBANK, HOLZBANK, GARDEROBE, GLASTISCH, NAEHTISCH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Vertretung, Ersatzkraft",
      "Antwort": "AUSHILFE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Boxkampfstätte",
      "Antwort": "RING"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ohne Inhalt",
      "Antwort": "HOHL, INAN, LEER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "österreichischer Fluss zur Donau",
      "Antwort": "KREMS, MARCH, NAARN, PRAUN, TRAUN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "spanische Anrede: Herr",
      "Antwort": "DON, SENOR"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "vertraute Anrede",
      "Antwort": "DU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "australischer Beutelbär",
      "Antwort": "BILBY, KOALA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "deutscher Dichter",
      "Antwort": "ARNT, DAHN, HEHN, HEIN, LENZ, MANN, ROTH, BOELL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "ehemalige portugiesische Münze",
      "Antwort": "BARBUDA, CENTAVO, MILREIS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Pädagogin",
      "Antwort": "LEHRERIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "spanisch: Fluss",
      "Antwort": "RIO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "afrikanischer Strom",
      "Antwort": "FIE, NIA, NIL, OMO, OMU, ZOU, AKOBO, KASAI, KOMOE, OGOWE, UELLE, VOLTA, MANGOKI, PANGANI, SEMLIKI, SENEGAL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fachliteratur",
      "Antwort": "SACHBUCH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Ungeziefer",
      "Antwort": "BRUT, FLOH, LAUS, MADE, MAUS, PACK, ASSEL, MILBE, MOTTE, RATTE, WANZE, ABSCHAUM, KAKERLAK, KANAILLE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Fürst von Monaco",
      "Antwort": "ALBERT, RAINER, REINJE, RAINIER"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "rückbezügliches Fürwort",
      "Antwort": "DICH, EUCH, MICH, SICH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Niederschlag",
      "Antwort": "FOG, TAU, BRUMA, DUNST, HAGEL, HARST, MOROK, NEBEL, EISREGEN, MAIREGEN, NASSAUER, EISNADELN, HAGELDORN, MORGENTAU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Niederlage, Zusammenbruch",
      "Antwort": "DEBAKEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "kleines Sportsegelboot",
      "Antwort": "DINGI, JOLLE, KAJAK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Rumgetränk",
      "Antwort": "GROG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Astrologe Wallensteins",
      "Antwort": "SENI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zeichen für Actinium",
      "Antwort": "AC"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zeichen für Silber",
      "Antwort": "AG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zeichen für Argentum",
      "Antwort": "AG"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zeichen für Amperestunde",
      "Antwort": "AH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zeichen für Bohrium",
      "Antwort": "BH"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Zeichen für Berkelium",
      "Antwort": "BK"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Omans",
      "Antwort": "MASKAT, MASQAT, MUSCAT"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Ohios",
      "Antwort": "COLUMBUS"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Gambias",
      "Antwort": "BANJUL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Ghanas",
      "Antwort": "ACCRA, AKKRA, NKRAN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Guineas",
      "Antwort": "CONAKRY"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Belgiens",
      "Antwort": "BRUESSEL"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Bahamas",
      "Antwort": "NASSAU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt vom US-Bundesstaat Texas",
      "Antwort": "AUSTIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt vom US-Bundesstaat Georgia",
      "Antwort": "ATLANTA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt vom US-Bundesstaat Louisiana",
      "Antwort": "BATONROUGE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt vom US-Bundesstaat Nevada",
      "Antwort": "CARSONCITY"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt vom US-Bundesstaat Maine",
      "Antwort": "AUGUSTA"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt vom US-Bundesstaat Alaska",
      "Antwort": "JUNEAU"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt vom US-Bundesstaat West Virginia",
      "Antwort": "CHARLESTON"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt vom US-Bundesstaat Arizona",
      "Antwort": "PHOENIX"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Chinas",
      "Antwort": "PEKING"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Costa Ricas",
      "Antwort": "JOSE, SANJOSE"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Dänemarks",
      "Antwort": "KOPENHAGEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Estlands",
      "Antwort": "REVAL, TALLINN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Ecuadors",
      "Antwort": "CUZCO, QUITO"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Finnlands",
      "Antwort": "HELSINKI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Hessens",
      "Antwort": "WIESBADEN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Iraks",
      "Antwort": "BAGDAD"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Indiens",
      "Antwort": "DEHLI, DELHI, NEUDEHLI, NEUDELHI"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Irlands",
      "Antwort": "DUBLIN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Irans",
      "Antwort": "TEHERAN"
    },
    {
      "Frage": "Hauptstadt Japans",
      "Antwort": "TOKIO"
    }
  ]
}
